<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility" type="xinstance" name="FacilityRadiationSafety" elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, MedicalOrganization, Department, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate, PeriodTypeCode, PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, ALARAExceededCases">
  <include name="CommonElements" prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName" appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
  <notes>TEST</notes>
  <documentation>ALARA (As Low As Reasonably Achievable) is a radiation safety principle for minimizing radiation doses and releases of radioactive materials by employing all reasonable methods.  ALARA is a sound safety principle as well as a regulatory requirement for all radiation safety programs.  Facility Radiation Safety enables the customer to populate the Actual, Projected, Budget or Benchmark ALARA levels by population groups for a facility, location, organization or department or any combination within that hierarchy for the reporting period.  </documentation>
  <element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
    <documentation>Specifies the physical medical facility where the patient received treatment.</documentation>
    <example>
      <Facility>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
      </Facility>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
    <documentation>If data pertains to a particular location within the facility such as a specific building, it is defined here.</documentation>
    <example>
      <FacilityLocation>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Building A</SourceInstanceId>
      </FacilityLocation>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="MedicalOrganization" type="link" contains="Organization">
    <documentation>Identifies the medical organization. This organization consists of a group of people working together to improve methods of health care delivery.</documentation>
    <example>
      <Organization>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Organization XYZ</SourceInstanceId>
      </Organization>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
    <documentation>If data pertains to a particular department within the organization such as the Emergency Room, it is defined here.</documentation>
    <example>
      <OrganizationalUnit>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Emergency Room</SourceInstanceId>
      </OrganizationalUnit>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
    <documentation>Contains the starting date when the facility statistics were collected.</documentation>
    <example>
      <PeriodStartDate format="yyy-MM-dd">2015-01-01</PeriodStartDate>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
    <documentation>Contains the ending date when the facility statistics were collected.</documentation>
    <example>
      <PeriodEndDate format="yyy-MM-dd">2015-01-01</PeriodEndDate>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="code">
    <documentation>Identifies the period of time that the facility statistics represent.</documentation>
    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PeriodTypeCodes">Year</example>
  </element>
  <element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="code">
    <documentation>These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for any metric for the reporting period. A single IDS can be for only one Planning Category/Subcategory combination. If the customer reports this at the departmental level, then each IDS represents one Department/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's down to the departmental level, or anything and everything in between. The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, but how the customer uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making comparisons. Actuals would capture the real statistics for the reporting period. If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula for a hospital or department of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the beginning of the fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.</documentation>
    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCodes">Projected</example>
  </element>
  <element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="code">
    <documentation>The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks IDS's for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.</documentation>
    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">50th percentile</example>
  </element>
  <list name="ALARAExceededCases">
    <documentation>ALARAExceededCases is a collection of ALARAExceededCase instances. ALARA is an acronym for As Low As Reasonably Achievable. It is a radiation safety principle for minimizing radiation doses and releases of radioactive materials by employing all reasonable methods. ALARA is a sound safety principle as well as a regulatory requirement for all radiation safety programs.</documentation>
  
	<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility" type="xinstance_child" name="ALARAExceededCase" elementOrder="RadiationSafetyPopulationTypeCode, RadiationSafetyPopulationSubTypeCode, ALARALevel, BodySiteCode, IndividualsExceedingALARALevelExposure">
	  <include name="CommonElements" prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName" appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
	  <notes>TEST</notes>
	  <documentation>ALARA is an acronym for As Low As Reasonably Achievable. It is a radiation safety principle for minimizing radiation doses and releases of radioactive materials by employing all reasonable methods.  ALARA is a sound safety principle as well as a regulatory requirement for all radiation safety programs.</documentation>
	  <element name="RadiationSafetyPopulationTypeCode" type="code">
	    <documentation>Safe radiation exposure differs by population group.</documentation>
	    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="RadiationSafetyPopulationTypeCodes">All</example>
	  </element>
	  <element name="RadiationSafetyPopulationSubTypeCode" type="code">
	    <documentation>The radiation safety population can further subcategorize the target population. For example, adults on staff have a higher allowable exposure level than pregnant women on staff.</documentation>
	    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="RadiationSafetyPopulationSubTypeCodes">Adults</example>
	  </element>
	  <element name="ALARALevel" type="integer">
	    <documentation>Contains the annual dose limit, measured in millirem, that should not be exceeded for the selected population group and body site. For example, X-ray technicians should not exceed 5,000 millirem to the whole body and skin should not be exposed to more than 50,000 millirem annually. The general public should not be exposed to more than 100 millirem annually. A fetus should not be exposed to more than 500 millirem during the gestation period.</documentation>
	    <example>
	      <ALARALevel>56</ALARALevel>
	    </example>
	  </element>
	  <element name="BodySiteCode" type="code">
	    <documentation>Identifies the anatomical location that was exposed to radiation.</documentation>
	    <example sourceName="Body Site" codeSet="Code - 0163">Whole Body</example>
	  </element>
	  <element name="IndividualsExceedingALARALevelExposure" type="integer">
	    <documentation>Specifies the number of persons that exceeded safe radiation exposure based on the recommended ALARA level.</documentation>
	    <example>
	      <IndividualsExceedingALARALevelExposure>34</IndividualsExceedingALARALevelExposure>
	    </example>
	  </element>
	</idsDocument>  
  </list>
</idsDocument>
