<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility" type="xinstance" name="FacilityRecall" elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, MedicalOrganization, Department, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate, PeriodTypeCode, PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, Recalls">
  <include name="CommonElements" prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName" appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
  <notes>TEST</notes>
  <documentation>When a product such as a medical device is discovered to pose a safety issue or be defective, it can be recalled to the manufacturer.  Analysis must be performed to identify the root-cause of the problem and determine how to rectify it in order to get the product back on the market after a recall.  Facility Recall enables the customer to populate the Actual, Projected, Budget or Benchmark recall statistics for a facility, location, organization or department or any combination within that hierarchy for the reporting period.</documentation>
  <element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
    <documentation>Specifies the physical medical facility where the patient received treatment.</documentation>
    <example>
      <Facility>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
      </Facility>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
    <documentation>If data pertains to a particular location within the facility such as a specific building, it is defined here.</documentation>
    <example>
      <FacilityLocation>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Building A</SourceInstanceId>
      </FacilityLocation>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="MedicalOrganization" type="link" contains="Organization">
    <documentation>Identifies the medical organization. This organization consists of a group of people working together to improve methods of health care delivery.</documentation>
    <example>
      <Organization>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Organization XYZ</SourceInstanceId>
      </Organization>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
    <documentation>If data pertains to a particular department within the organization such as the Emergency Room, it is defined here.</documentation>
    <example>
      <OrganizationalUnit>
        <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
        <SourceInstanceId>Emergency Room</SourceInstanceId>
      </OrganizationalUnit>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
    <documentation>Contains the starting date when the facility statistics were collected.</documentation>
    <example>
      <PeriodStartDate format="yyy-MM-dd">2015-01-01</PeriodStartDate>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
    <documentation>Contains the ending date when the facility statistics were collected.</documentation>
    <example>
      <PeriodEndDate format="yyy-MM-dd">2015-01-01</PeriodEndDate>
    </example>
  </element>
  <element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="code">
    <documentation>Identifies the period of time that the facility statistics represent.</documentation>
    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PeriodTypeCodes">Year</example>
  </element>
  <element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="code">
    <documentation>These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for any metric for the reporting period. A single IDS can be for only one Planning Category/Subcategory combination. If the customer reports this at the departmental level, then each IDS represents one Department/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's down to the departmental level, or anything and everything in between. The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, but how the customer uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making comparisons. Actuals would capture the real statistics for the reporting period. If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula for a hospital or department of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the beginning of the fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.</documentation>
    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCodes">Projected</example>
  </element>
  <element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="code">
    <documentation>The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks IDS's for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.</documentation>
    <example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">50th percentile</example>
  </element>
  <group name="Recalls" elementOrder="NumberOfRecalls, NumberOfRecallsCompliedWith">
    <documentation>Recalls is a group of attributes to track the number of product recalls and those compliant with new specifications fixing defects.</documentation>

	  <element name="NumberOfRecalls" type="integer">
		<documentation>For each recall, analysis is performed to determine which products are defective. It may be limited to a particular batch of the product or include the entire production run.</documentation>
		<example>
		  <NumberOfRecalls>2</NumberOfRecalls>
		</example>
	  </element>
	  <element name="NumberOfRecallsCompliedWith" type="integer">
		<documentation>Once the root-cause of the problem is identified, risk analyses is performed to develop new specifications for fixing the product. Compliance of a recalled product involves conforming to the corrective specifications of the product.</documentation>
		<example>
		  <NumberOfRecallsCompliedWith>6</NumberOfRecallsCompliedWith>
		</example>
	  </element>
  </group>
</idsDocument>
