<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility"
	type="xinstance" name="FacilityFireSafety"
	elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, MedicalOrganization, Department, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate, PeriodTypeCode, PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, FireEmergencyTrainingCompleted, TotalFireSystemInspectionsRequired, FireDrillMetrics, FireAlarmActivations">
	
	<include name="CommonElements"
		prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
		appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy" />
	
	<documentation>Facility Fire Safety enables the customer to populate
		the Actual, Projected, Budget or Benchmark fire safety metrics for a
		facility, location, organization or department or any combination
		within that hierarchy for the reporting period. These fire safety
		metrics include fire drills, fire alarm activations, number of fire
		system inspections required and whether fire emergency training has
		been completed at the facility.</documentation>
	
	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>Specifies the physical medical facility where the
			patient received treatment.</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
		<documentation>If data pertains to a particular location within the
			facility such as a specific building, it is defined here.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="MedicalOrganization" type="link" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>Identifies the medical organization. This organization
			consists of a group of people working together to improve methods of
			health care delivery.</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>If data pertains to a particular department within the
			organization such as the Emergency Room, it is defined here.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>Contains the starting date when the facility statistics
			were collected.</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>Contains the ending date when the facility statistics
			were collected.</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>Identifies the period of time that the facility
			statistics represent.</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted,
			Projected or Benchmarks for any metric for the reporting period. A
			single IDS can be for only one Planning Category/Subcategory
			combination. If the customer reports this at the departmental level,
			then each IDS represents one Department/Category/Subcategory
			combination. The customer can generate these at multiple levels if
			they so choose. IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's down to the
			departmental level, or anything and everything in between. The
			distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term)
			is generally accepted, but how the customer uses these categories is
			up to them; they just enable a means of making comparisons. Actuals
			would capture the real statistics for the reporting period. If they
			are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there
			is an industry formula for a hospital or department of their size.
			Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for different
			percentiles, if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the
			beginning of the fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate
			these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks IDS's for different
			percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="FireEmergencyTrainingCompleted" type="code">
		<documentation>Indicates whether fire emergency training has been
			completed at the facility. If "Yes", training has been completed. If
			"No", training has not been completed.</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="TotalFireSystemInspectionsRequired" type="integer">
		<documentation>Contains the number of fire system inspections required
			at the facility for the reporting period.</documentation>
	</element>

	<group name="FireDrillMetrics"
		elementOrder="FireDrillsCompliant, AverageFireDrillCompositeScore, AverageFireDrillScoreAtScene, 
				      AverageFireDrillScoreAwayFromScene, AverageFireDrillScoreSystemPerformance, 
				      AverageFireDrillScoreCodeRedDrillReports, NumberOfIssuesIdentifiedDuringFireDrills">
		
		<documentation>FireDrillMetrics is a group of attributes representing
			different fire drill scores and number of issues identified during
			the fire drills at the facility for the reporting period.
		</documentation>

		<element name="FireDrillsCompliant" type="double">
			<documentation>Contains the percentage of compliant fire drills at
				the facility for the reporting period.</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageFireDrillCompositeScore" type="double">
			<documentation>Contains the average fire drill composite score.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageFireDrillScoreAtScene" type="double">
			<documentation>Contains the average fire drill score at the scene.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageFireDrillScoreAwayFromScene" type="double">
			<documentation>Contains the average fire drill score away from the
				scene.</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageFireDrillScoreSystemPerformance" type="double">
			<documentation>Contains the average fire drill score on system
				performance.</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageFireDrillScoreCodeRedDrillReports" type="double">
			<documentation>Contains the average fire drill score on Code Red
				drill reports. Code Red is used by hospitals to announce message
				that a fire is occurring in the facility indicating that emergency
				measures should be taken.</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfIssuesIdentifiedDuringFireDrills" type="integer">
			<documentation>Contains the number of issues identified during the
				fire drills at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	</group>
	
	<list name="FireAlarmActivations">
		<documentation>FireAlarmActivations is a collection of
			FireAlarmActivation instances. Captures the type and count of fire
			alarm activations at the facility for the reporting period.
		</documentation>

		<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility"
			type="xinstance_child" name="FireAlarmActivation"
			elementOrder="FacilityAlarmTypeCode, NumberOfFacilityAlarmActivations">

			<include name="CommonElements"
				prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
				appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy" />

			<documentation>Captures the type and count of alarm activations at
				the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>

			<element name="FacilityAlarmTypeCode" type="code">
				<documentation>There are different ways to trigger the facility
					alarm which represent different types of activations.
				</documentation>
			</element>
			
			<element name="NumberOfFacilityAlarmActivations" type="integer">
				<documentation>Contains the number of alarm activations that
					occurred at the facility for the reporting period.</documentation>
			</element>
		</idsDocument>
	</list>
</idsDocument>
