<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility" type="xinstance"
			 name="FacilityCapabilities"  
	 		 elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, MedicalOrganization, Department, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate, 
					PeriodTypeCode, PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, Capabilities"
			 >
	 		               	
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>
	

	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>

	<notes> 
	 
	</notes>
			
	<documentation>
	Facility Capabilities captures various metrics for a specified facility such as the type of facility 
	(federally run, acute care, critical care access, etc.), whether it is part of an Accountable Care Organization, 
	how Electronic Health Records are used and what security measures have been implemented to protect patient data, 
	type of data that is submitted to different registries, whether use the Physician Quality Reporting System, 
	Clinical Decision Support, Clinical Quality Measures, etc.  Facility Capabilities enables the customer to 
	populate the Actual, Projected, Budget or Benchmark assessment metrics for a facility, location, organization 
	or department or any combination within that hierarchy for the reporting period.
	</documentation>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the physical medical facility where the patient received treatment.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<Facility>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
			</Facility>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
		<documentation>
		If data pertains to a particular location within the facility such as a specific building, it is defined here.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<FacilityLocation>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Building A</SourceInstanceId>
			</FacilityLocation>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalOrganization" type="link" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the medical organization. This organization consists of a group of people working together to improve methods of health care delivery.
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<Organization>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Medical Center</SourceInstanceId>
			</Organization>
		</example>
			
	</element>

	<element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
		If data pertains to a particular department within the organization such as the Emergency Room, it is defined here.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<OrganizationalUnit>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Emergency Room</SourceInstanceId>
			</OrganizationalUnit>
		</example>
	</element>
	
	<element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the starting date when the facility statistics were collected.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodStartDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-01-01
			</PeriodStartDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the ending date when the facility statistics were collected.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodEndDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-02-02
			</PeriodEndDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the period of time that the facility statistics represent.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PeriodTypeCodes">
			Year
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for any metric 
		for the reporting period. A single IDS can be for only one Planning Category/Subcategory combination. 
		If the customer reports this at the departmental level, then each IDS represents one 
		Department/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. 
		IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's down to the departmental level, or anything and everything in between. 

		The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, 
		but how the customer uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making comparisons.  
		Actuals would capture the real statistics for the reporting period.

		If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula for 
		a hospital or department of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for different percentiles, 
		if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the beginning of the fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCode">
			Projected
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks IDS's 
		for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">
			50th percentile
		</example>
	</element>

	<group name="Capabilities" elementOrder="ACOMembership, FederalFacility, AcuteCareHospital, CriticalCareAccessFacility, PrimaryCarePhysician,
						MedicareEHRQualificationDate, PQRSEHRSystemUsed, FQHCFacility, RHCFacility, ClinicalDecisionSupportRuleImplemented,
						ClinicalQualityMeasuresReported, ClinicalInformationExchangeCapability, ProtectClinicalHealthInformation,
						DrugFormularyChecksImplemented, GeneratingReportsForQualityImprovement,	CapableToSubmitImmunizationDataToRegistries,
						CapableToSubmitElectronicLabResultData, CapableToSubmitElectronicSyndromicSurveillanceData, 							ProvidesPatientsElectronicAccessToHealthData, ProvidesPatientSpecificEducationalResources,
						ReportedToPatientClinicalDataRegistry, ImplementedClinDecSuppToImprovePerfHighPriorityHealthConditions,
						SuccessfullyTestedCMSDesignatedTestEHR, ExchangedSummCareWithDifferentEHRTechnology,
						RecipTransSummCareSentElecToNwHINExchange, RulesEstablishedForTransWithHealthInfoNetworkFollowed,
						SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTAuth, SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTAudit, SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTStoredData,
						SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTEndUserDeviceEncrypt, CapableToSubmitCancerCaseDataToPublicCancerRegistry,
						CapableToSubmitSpecificCaseDataToSpecializedRegistry, IncorporatedNecessaryCQMReportingIntoEHRSystem">
		<documentation>
		
		</documentation>

		<element name="ACOMembership" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if participating in ACO membership.  According to the Centers for Medicare and 
			Medicaid Services (CMS), an ACO is "an organization of healthcare providers that agrees to be 
			accountable for the quality, cost, and overall care of Medicare beneficiaries who are enrolled 
			in the traditional fee-for-service program who are assigned to it." In other words, an Accountable 
			Care Organization (ACO) is a multi-dimensional healthcare organization characterized by a payment 
			and care delivery model that seeks to tie provider reimbursements to quality metrics and reductions 
			in the total cost of care for an assigned population of patients.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="FederalFacility" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether this is a federal facility.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="AcuteCareHospital" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether this is an acute care hospital.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CriticalCareAccessFacility" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether this is a critical care access facility.	
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PrimaryCarePhysician" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Is primary care physician.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="MedicareEHRQualificationDate" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
			Effective date of medicare EHR (Electronic Health Record) qualification.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<MedicareEHRQualificationDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
					2015-01-01
				</MedicareEHRQualificationDate>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PQRSEHRSystemUsed" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the facility uses a PQRS (Physician Quality Reporting System) EHR system.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="FQHCFacility" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether this is a Federally Qualified Healthcare Center.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="RHCFacility" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether this is a Rural Health Clinic.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ClinicalDecisionSupportRuleImplemented" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the institution implemented clinical decision support rule and its ability to track it.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ClinicalQualityMeasuresReported" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether  the institution has the ability to report clinical quality measures (CQM) to 
			Centers for Medicare and Medicate Services (CMS) or the States.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ClinicalInformationExchangeCapability" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution has the capability for clinical information exchange.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ProtectClinicalHealthInformation" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution has taken the necessary steps to protect clinical health information.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="DrugFormularyChecksImplemented" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution has implemented drug formulary checks.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="GeneratingReportsForQualityImprovement" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution is generating reports for quality improvements.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CapableToSubmitImmunizationDataToRegistries" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution has the capability to submit electronic data to immunization registries 
			or Immunization Information Systems and actual submission in accordance with applicable law and practice.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CapableToSubmitElectronicLabResultData" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution has the capability to send lab results electronically.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CapableToSubmitElectronicSyndromicSurveillanceData" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution has the capability to submit electronic syndromic surveillance data to 
			public health agencies and actual submission in accordance with applicable law and practice.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ProvidesPatientsElectronicAccessToHealthData" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution is able to provide patient access to health information electronically.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ProvidesPatientSpecificEducationalResources" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution provides educational resources specific to patient needs and diagnosis.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ReportedToPatientClinicalDataRegistry" type="code">
			<documentation>
			States whether a complete and appropriate patient data was reported to a qualified clinical database registry or not.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ImplementedClinDecSuppToImprovePerfHighPriorityHealthConditions" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the institution implemented the requirement for the clinical decision support 
			rules to improve performance on high-priority health conditions.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="SuccessfullyTestedCMSDesignatedTestEHR" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if institution has conducted one or more successful tests with the CMS designated test EHR.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ExchangedSummCareWithDifferentEHRTechnology" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if institution has conducted one or more successful electronic exchanges of a 
			summary of care document with a recipient who has EHR technology that was designed by a 
			different EHR technology developer than the sender's EHR technology.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="RecipTransSummCareSentElecToNwHINExchange" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the recipient of transitions summary of care of patient was sent electronically to a 
			member of the NwHIN (Nationwide Health Information Network) Exchange.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="RulesEstablishedForTransWithHealthInfoNetworkFollowed" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the rules established for receiving and sending transitions summary of care of patients 
			by the ONC for the nationwide health information network were followed.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTAuth" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the EP's (Eligible Professional), EH's (Eligible Hospital), or CAH's (Critical Access Hospital) 
			have conducted or reviewed a security risk analysis in accordance with the requirements of data stored in 
			CEHRT (Certified EHR Technology).  Pertains to authentication, access control and authorization.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTAudit" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the EP's, EH's, or CAH's conducted or reviewed a security risk analysis in accordance 
			with the requirements of data the stored in CEHRT. Pertains to Auditable events and tamper-resistance 
			(record actions, record the audit log status, record the encryption status, default setting, 
			when disabling the audit log is permitted and audit log protection).
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTStoredData" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the EP's, EH's, or CAH's conducted or reviewed a security risk analysis in accordance with the 
			requirements of data the stored in CEHRT. Pertains to stored data (audit reports, amendments, automatic log-off and emergency access).
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="SecurityRiskAnalysisCEHRTEndUserDeviceEncrypt" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if the EP's, EH's, or CAH's conducted or reviewed a security risk analysis in accordance 
			with the requirements of data the stored in CEHRT. Pertains to end-user device encryption.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CapableToSubmitCancerCaseDataToPublicCancerRegistry" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if EP must have the capability to submit cancer case information from CEHRT to a 
			public health central cancer registry. 
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CapableToSubmitSpecificCaseDataToSpecializedRegistry" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if EP must have the capability to submit specific case information from CEHRT to specialized registry.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="IncorporatedNecessaryCQMReportingIntoEHRSystem" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates if EP's or EH's have incorporated the necessary CQM (Clinical Quality Measure) reporting 
			rules in their respective EHR systems.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y =Yes
			</example>
		</element>				
	</group>	
</idsDocument>
