<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility" type="xinstance"
			 name="FacilityOperations"  
	 		 elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, MedicalOrganization, Department, AccountCode, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate, 
					PeriodTypeCode, PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, CurrencyCode, Capacity, Utilities, Cleaning,
					Maintenance, Services, Transportation, Medevac, "
			 >
	 		               	
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>
	

	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>

	<notes> 
	 
	</notes>
			
	<documentation>
	Facility Operations enables the customer to populate the Actual, Projected, Budget or Benchmark individual or 
	aggregated facility operational and maintenance totals by facility, location, organization or department 
	or any combination within that hierarchy for the reporting period.  General areas of collected statistics 
	include Capacity (daily bed occupancy, ER capacity, OR capacity, occupied area), Utilities (water consumed, 
	total energy costs, downtime hours due to utility failure), Cleaning (average time to clean room), Maintenance 
	(building maintenance costs, number work orders past due, total work orders received), Services 
	(landscaping costs, mail distribution time), Transportation (number of drivers, repair costs, fuel costs, miles driven),
	Medevac (helicopter arrivals and departures), Parking (number cars parked, parking capacity, parking revenue) and Ambulances 
	(type of vehicle, VIN, fuel purchased costs, is it cleaned, serviced, operational, transport response time, total miles driven).
	</documentation>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the physical medical facility associated with the facility operations being reported.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<Facility>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
			</Facility>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
		<documentation>
		If facility operations are being captured at a physical location within the facility such as a specific building, it is defined here.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<FacilityLocation>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Building A</SourceInstanceId>
			</FacilityLocation>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalOrganization" type="link" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the medical organization associated with the facility operations being reported.
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<Organization>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Medical Center</SourceInstanceId>
			</Organization>
		</example>
			
	</element>

	<element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
		If facility operations are being captured at a department within the organization such as the Emergency Room, it is defined here.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<OrganizationalUnit>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Emergency Room</SourceInstanceId>
			</OrganizationalUnit>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="AccountCode" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the code assigned to an account that represents the facility or department referenced.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<AccountCode>
				20101
			</AccountCode>
		</example>
	</element>
	
	<element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the starting date when the facility operation statistics were collected.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodStartDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-01-01
			</PeriodStartDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the ending date when the facility operation statistics were collected.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodEndDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-02-02
			</PeriodEndDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the period of time that the facility operation statistics represent.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PeriodTypeCodes">
			Year
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for any metric 
		for the reporting period. A single IDS can be for only one Planning Category/Subcategory combination. 
		If the customer reports this at the departmental level, then each IDS represents one 
		Department/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. 
		IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's down to the departmental level, or anything and everything in between. 

		The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, 
		but how the customer uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making comparisons.  
		Actuals would capture the real statistics for the reporting period.

		If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula for 
		a hospital or department of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for different percentiles, 
		if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the beginning of the fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCode">
			Projected
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks IDS's 
		for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">
			50th percentile
		</example>
	</element>
		
	<element name="CurrencyCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the denomination for all amounts using the industry standard defined in the ISO 4217 code set.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="ISO4217" codeSet="4217">
			USD
		</example>
	</element>

	<group name="Capacity" elementOrder="TotalFloorSpace, TotalFloorSpaceUnitOfMeasureCode, OccupiedArea, EmergencyRoomCapacity, OperatingRoomCapacity, LabCapacity,
						PharmacyCapacity, RadiologyCapacity, TotalFacilityCapacity, OccupiedBeds">
		<documentation>
		Capacity is a group of attributes to track a facility's measurable resources such as the square footage 
		of the facility, percentage of occupied space at the facility, number of occupied beds, number of patients 
		who can be treated in the emergency room, number of lab orders processed, number of medication orders serviced 
		and number of radiology orders serviced for the reporting period.
		</documentation>

		<element name="TotalFloorSpace" type="double">
			<documentation>
			It is the measure of the area for the selected facility or location such as a building.
			Example---- square feet ---- square meter
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TotalFloorSpace>
					30000
				</TotalFloorSpace>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalFloorSpaceUnitOfMeasureCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Represents the total floor space unit of measure for the selected facility or location such as a building.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="ISO, ISO+, ANSI+" codeSet="6020">
			square meters
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="OccupiedArea" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Specifies how much of the area at the facility is occupied for the reporting period expressed as a percent.  
			The following example demonstrates how this value is used:  Measure "Building and Maintenance Cost / Occupied 
			Area (%)" is the cost of maintaining buildings and facility built up area by total occupied area for the facility 
			over a period of time.  If cost is $200 and 50% of the facility is occupied, the cost to maintain the building would 
			be $400 if the facility was operating at 100% occupancy.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<OccupiedArea>
					30
				</OccupiedArea>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="EmergencyRoomCapacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the number of patients who can be treated in the emergency room of the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<EmergencyRoomCapacity>
					23
				</EmergencyRoomCapacity>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="OperatingRoomCapacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the number of patients who can undergo operations in the operating room of the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<OperatingRoomCapacity>
					20
				</OperatingRoomCapacity>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="LabCapacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the number of lab orders that can be processed in the lab for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<LabCapacity>
					4
				</LabCapacity>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PharmacyCapacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the number of medication orders that can be serviced by the pharmacy for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<PharmacyCapacity>
					10
				</PharmacyCapacity>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="RadiologyCapacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the number of radiology orders that can be serviced in the radiology department for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<RadiologyCapacity>
					34
				</RadiologyCapacity>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalFacilityCapacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the number of patients who can be treated at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<TotalFacilityCapacity>
					23
				</TotalFacilityCapacity>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="OccupiedBeds" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the number of occupied beds at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<OccupiedBeds>
					12
				</OccupiedBeds>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Utilities" elementOrder="WaterConsumption, ElectricityConsumed, BTUsConsumed, TotalEnergyCosts, HVACFiltersReplaced, TotalHVACFilters, WaterLevelScore,
						UtilityFailures, UtilityFailureDowntimeHours">
		<documentation>
		Utilities is a group of attributes to track a facility's resource and energy consumption for the reporting period.  In addition, 
		it captures statistics on maintenance such as air filters and water quality, as well as utility failures and resulting downtime.  
		</documentation>

		<element name="WaterConsumption" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total amount of water in gallons consumed at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<WaterConsumption>
					50
				</WaterConsumption>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="ElectricityConsumed" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total amount of electrical energy in KWH consumed at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<ElectricityConsumed>
					2
				</ElectricityConsumed>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="BTUsConsumed" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total amount of electrical energy in BTUs consumed at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<BTUsConsumed>
					12
				</BTUsConsumed>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalEnergyCosts" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total cost of energy at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TotalEnergyCosts>
					23455
				</TotalEnergyCosts>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="HVACFiltersReplaced" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of HVAC filters that were replaced at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<HVACFiltersReplaced>
					23
				</HVACFiltersReplaced>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalHVACFilters" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of HVAC filters at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<TotalHVACFilters>
					23
				</TotalHVACFilters>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="WaterLevelScore" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The level of water quality at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<WaterLevelScore>
					23
				</WaterLevelScore>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="UtilityFailures" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of utility failures such as a power outage at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<UtilityFailures>
					23
				</UtilityFailures>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="UtilityFailureDowntimeHours" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The number of hours representing the duration of the utility failure at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<UtilityFailureDowntimeHours>
					12
				</UtilityFailureDowntimeHours>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Cleaning" elementOrder="SoiledLaundryInBags, CleanLaundryInBags, RoomCleaningTime">
		<documentation>  
		Cleaning is a group of attributes to track laundry processed and time to clean rooms at a facility for the reporting period.
		</documentation>

		<element name="SoiledLaundryInBags" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of soiled laundry bags sent out to be cleaned from the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<SoiledLaundryInBags>
					23
				</SoiledLaundryInBags>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CleanLaundryInBags" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of cleaned laundry bags received at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<CleanLaundryInBags>
					23
				</CleanLaundryInBags>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="RoomCleaningTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The time, in minutes, taken to clean an inpatient room from the time of notification at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<RoomCleaningTime>
					12
				</RoomCleaningTime>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Maintenance" elementOrder="BuildingMaintenanceCost, PreventiveMaintenanceHours, FacilityInspectionsCompleted, TotalFacilityInspectionsRequired,
						WorkOrdersPastDue, TotalWorkOrdersReceived, TotalWorkOrdersCompleted, CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived,
						CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted, PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived, PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted,
						OnDemandWorkHours, SystemFailureRate">
		<documentation>  
		Maintenance is a group of attributes to track the preventative and routine facility maintenance costs, inspections, work orders, 
		hours performed and system failure rates for the reporting period.
		</documentation>

		<element name="BuildingMaintenanceCost" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The cost of maintaining buildings that are part of the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<BuildingMaintenanceCost>
					12
				</BuildingMaintenanceCost>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PreventiveMaintenanceHours" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number of hours spent on preventive maintenance work at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<PreventiveMaintenanceHours>
					12
				</PreventiveMaintenanceHours>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="FacilityInspectionsCompleted" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of facility inspections completed at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<FacilityInspectionsCompleted>
					23
				</FacilityInspectionsCompleted>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalFacilityInspectionsRequired" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of facility inspections required at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<TotalFacilityInspectionsRequired>
					45
				</TotalFacilityInspectionsRequired>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="WorkOrdersPastDue" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of work orders past due at the facility during a given period of time.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<WorkOrdersPastDue>
					23
				</WorkOrdersPastDue>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalWorkOrdersReceived" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of all maintenance work orders received at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<TotalWorkOrdersReceived>
					45
				</TotalWorkOrdersReceived>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalWorkOrdersCompleted" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number of all maintenance work orders completed at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TotalWorkOrdersCompleted>
					12
				</TotalWorkOrdersCompleted>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number of corrective maintenance work orders received at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived>
					12
				</CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number of corrective maintenance work orders completed at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted>
					12
				</CorrectiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number of preventative maintenance work orders received at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived>
					12
				</PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersReceived>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number of preventative maintenance work orders completed at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted>
					12
				</PreventiveMaintenanceWorkOrdersCompleted>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="OnDemandWorkHours" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number of hours categorized as "On Demand" work at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<OnDemandWorkHours>
					12
				</OnDemandWorkHours>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="SystemFailureRate" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The rate at which the system fails at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<SystemFailureRate>
					12
				</SystemFailureRate>
			</example>
		</element>		
	</group>
	
	<group name="Services" elementOrder="GroundsAndGardenCosts, MailDistributionTime, ParenteralNutritionPreps">
		<documentation>  
		Services is a group of attributes to track some general facility operation services such as landscaping and grounds costs, 
		time to distribute mail and feed solutions prepared for patients receiving parenteral nutrition for the reporting period.
		</documentation>

		<element name="GroundsAndGardenCosts" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total cost of maintaining grounds and garden at the facility during a period of time.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<GroundsAndGardenCosts>
					23
				</GroundsAndGardenCosts>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="MailDistributionTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The time taken to distribute incoming mail from the time of receipt at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<MailDistributionTime>
					23
				</MailDistributionTime>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ParenteralNutritionPreps" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Parenteral feeding is the intravenous administration of nutrients.  It may be supplemental in addition to nutrients 
			received orally or through a tube or it can be a patient's entire source of nutrition, also known as total parenteral nutrition.  
			This attribute captures the number of feed solutions prepared at the facility for the reporting period..
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<ParenteralNutritionPreps>
					12
				</ParenteralNutritionPreps>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Transportation" elementOrder="DriverLicensesChecked, NumberOfDrivers, MaintenanceAndRepairCosts, CostForAtFaultAccidents, AtFaultAccidents, PercentAtFaultAccidents,
							FuelCosts, FuelByVolume, FuelByVolumeUnitOfMeasureCode, MilesDriven">
		<documentation>  
		Transportation is a group of attributes to track vehicle-related statistics at a facility for the reporting period.  
		This would include vehicle maintenance and repair costs, accident-related statistics, number of drivers, driver verification, 
		miles driven, fuel usage and costs.
		</documentation>

		<element name="DriverLicensesChecked" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of driver license that have been checked at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<DriverLicensesChecked>
					12
				</DriverLicensesChecked>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfDrivers" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of drivers who operate the facility's fleet.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<NumberOfDrivers>
					12
				</NumberOfDrivers>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="MaintenanceAndRepairCosts" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total cost involved in maintaining and repairing the fleet at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<MaintenanceAndRepairCosts>
					23
				</MaintenanceAndRepairCosts>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="CostForAtFaultAccidents" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The gross cost involved in at-fault accidents for the facility's fleet for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<CostForAtFaultAccidents>
					45
				</CostForAtFaultAccidents>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="AtFaultAccidents" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of at-fault accidents in the fleet at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<AtFaultAccidents>
					23
				</AtFaultAccidents>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PercentAtFaultAccidents" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The rate of at-fault accidents that occur in the fleet per 100,000 miles at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<PercentAtFaultAccidents>
					45
				</PercentAtFaultAccidents>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="FuelCosts" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total cost of fuel purchased in dollars for the fleet at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<FuelCosts>
					12
				</FuelCosts>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="FuelByVolume" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Total amount of fuel purchased for the fleet at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<FuelByVolume>
					12
				</FuelByVolume>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="FuelByVolumeUnitOfMeasureCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Represents the unit of measure to be used with the fuel volume.
			</documentation>
		
			<example sourceName="ISO, ISO+, ANSI+" codeSet="6020">
			gallon
			</example>
		</element>


		<element name="MilesDriven" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total number miles driven by drivers of the facility's fleet at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<MilesDriven>
					12
				</MilesDriven>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Medevac" elementOrder="HelicopterArrivalsDepartures, HelicopteredPatientArrivals, HelicopteredPatientDepartures">
		<documentation>  
		Medevac is the transport of someone to a hospital in a helicopter or airplane for the reporting period.  This group of attributes 
		tracks the number of patient arrivals and departures to a hospital in a helicopter.
		</documentation>

		<element name="HelicopterArrivalsDepartures" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of helicopter round-trips at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<HelicopterArrivalsDepartures>
					23
				</HelicopterArrivalsDepartures>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="HelicopteredPatientArrivals" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of helicopter arrivals while transporting a patient to the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<HelicopteredPatientArrivals>
					23
				</HelicopteredPatientArrivals>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="HelicopteredPatientDepartures" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of helicopter departures while transporting a patient away from the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<HelicopteredPatientDepartures>
					12
				</HelicopteredPatientDepartures>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Parking" elementOrder="CarsParked, Capacity, PatientParkingDeclined, TotalRevenue, TotalParkingDeclined, StaffParkingDeclined, AverageExitWaitTime,
						ValetCarsParked, ValetParkingCapacity, AverageRetrievalTime">
		<documentation>  
		Parking is a group of attributes to track parking lot usage for a specific facility or location within the facility for the reporting period.  
		This would include the parking lot capacity, number of parked cars, parking revenue, declined parking and valet-related parking statistics.
		</documentation>

		<element name="CarsParked" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of cars parked at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<CarsParked>
					12
				</CarsParked>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="Capacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the average number of parking spaces available at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<Capacity>
					12
				</Capacity>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PatientParkingDeclined" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of patient cars that were denied parking due to unavailability of parking space at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<PatientParkingDeclined>
					23
				</PatientParkingDeclined>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalRevenue" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The revenue received from parking facilities at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<TotalRevenue>
					45
				</TotalRevenue>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TotalParkingDeclined" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of cars turned away from parking due to unavailability of parking spaces at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<TotalParkingDeclined>
					23
				</TotalParkingDeclined>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="StaffParkingDeclined" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of staff cars turned away from parking due to unavailability of parking spaces at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<StaffParkingDeclined>
					45
				</StaffParkingDeclined>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageExitWaitTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The average wait time, in minutes, for cars at the exit gate of the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<AverageExitWaitTime>
					12
				</AverageExitWaitTime>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ValetCarsParked" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of cars parked by a valet at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<ValetCarsParked>
					12
				</ValetCarsParked>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ValetParkingCapacity" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the average number of valet parking spaces available at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<ValetParkingCapacity>
					12
				</ValetParkingCapacity>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="AverageRetrievalTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The average time, in minutes, taken for a valet to retrieve cars from valet parking at the facility for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<AverageRetrievalTime>
					12
				</AverageRetrievalTime>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<list name="Ambulances">
		<documentation>
		Ambulances is a collection of Ambulance instances.  An ambulance is used for the transport of a wounded or sick person to a place for treatment, 
		typically a hospital.  Paramedics may provide medical treatment while in route to the hospital.  This group of attributes tracks the ambulance 
		identification, type of vehicle, fuel purchased costs, miles driven, driver accidents and moving violations, maintenance and repair costs, 
		whether vehicle needs service, is operational, clean and available for the reporting period.
		</documentation>
		
			<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Facility" type="xinstance_child"
				 name="Ambulance"  
		 		 elementOrder="VehicleId, SerialNumber, VIN, VehicleTypeCode, FuelPurchasedByVolume, FuelPurchasedByVolumeUnitOfMeasureCode, FuelPurchasedCosts,
						TotalMaintenanceRepairCosts, GrossCostForAtFaultAccidents, CleanedIndicator, FuelLevel, ServicedIndicator, AtFaultAccidentsReported, 
						TotalDistanceDriven, TotalDistanceDrivenUnitOfMeasureCode, OperationalIndicator, AvailableIndicator">
		<include name="CommonElements" prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName" appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
		 		               	
		<changeLog>
			<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
		</changeLog>
	
		<notes> 
		</notes>
				
		<documentation>
		An ambulance is used for the transport of a wounded or sick person to a place for treatment, typically a hospital.  Paramedics may provide medical 
		treatment while in route to the hospital.  This group of attributes tracks the ambulance identification, type of vehicle, fuel purchased costs, 
		miles driven, driver accidents and moving violations, maintenance and repair costs, whether vehicle needs service, is operational, clean and 
		available for the reporting period.
		</documentation>
	
		<element name="VehicleId" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Represents a unique identifier separate from its VIN or serial number.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<VehicleId>
					M3G45
				</VehicleId>
			</example>
		</element>
			
		<element name="SerialNumber" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Represents the serial number of the vehicle, generally assigned by the manufacturer.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<SerialNumber>
					123564
				</SerialNumber>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="VIN" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Represents the vehicle identification number used in the automotive industry to uniquely identity all vehicles.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<VIN>
					35463
				</VIN>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="VehicleTypeCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Represents a classification for the ambulance such as emergency ambulance, patient transport ambulance, response unit, 
			bariatric ambulance, etc.  An emergency ambulance is used for patients with acute illness or injury.   A patient transport 
			ambulance is primarily used for non-urgent care to transport patients to and from places of medical treatment such as a dialysis center. 
			A response unit ambulance is used to reach an acutely ill patient quickly to provide treatment to the patient at the scene, but it lacks 
			capacity to transport the patient from the scene.  A bariatric ambulance is a special type of transport designed for extremely obese patients.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="VehicleTypeCode">
			Emergency Ambulance
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="FuelPurchasedByVolume" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Total volume of fuel purchased for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<FuelPurchasedByVolume>
					35463
				</FuelPurchasedByVolume>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="FuelPurchasedByVolumeUnitOfMeasureCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Represents the unit of measure to be used with the volume of fuel purchased.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="ISO, ISO+, ANSI+" codeSet="6020">
			gallon
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="FuelPurchasedCosts" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Total cost of fuel purchased for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<FuelPurchasedCosts>
					363.00
				</FuelPurchasedCosts>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TotalMaintenanceRepairCosts" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Total amount spent on maintenance and repair of ambulance for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<TotalMaintenanceRepairCosts>
					363.00
				</TotalMaintenanceRepairCosts>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="GrossCostForAtFaultAccidents" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Total cost of at-fault accidents reported involving this ambulance for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<GrossCostForAtFaultAccidents>
					363.00
				</GrossCostForAtFaultAccidents>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="MovingViolationsReported" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Number of moving violations reported involving this ambulance for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<MovingViolationsReported>
					36
				</MovingViolationsReported>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="CleanedIndicator" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the ambulance has been cleaned.  If "Yes", ambulance has been cleaned.  If "No", ambulance has not been cleaned.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y = Yes
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="FuelLevel" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Represents the fuel level in the ambulance.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<FuelLevel>
					3.00
				</FuelLevel>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="ServicedIndicator" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the ambulance has been serviced.  If "Yes", ambulance has been serviced.  If "No", ambulance has not been serviced.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y = Yes
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="AtFaultAccidentsReported" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of at-fault accidents reported involving this ambulance for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<AtFaultAccidentsReported>
					36
				</AtFaultAccidentsReported>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TotalDistanceDriven" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total distance driven in this ambulance for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<TotalDistanceDriven>
					363.00
				</TotalDistanceDriven>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TotalDistanceDrivenUnitOfMeasureCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Represents the unit of measure to be used with the total distance driven.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="ISO, ISO+, ANSI+" codeSet="6020">
			mile
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="OperationalIndicator" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the ambulance is operational.  If "Yes", ambulance is operational.  If "No", ambulance is not operational.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y = Yes
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="AvailableIndicator" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the ambulance is available for use.  If "Yes", ambulance is available.  If "No", ambulance is not available.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y = Yes
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TransportResponseTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The number of minutes from the transport request for the ambulance to arrive at its destination.
			</documentation>
				
			<example>
				<TransportResponseTime>
					45.78
				</TransportResponseTime>
			</example>
		</element>	
	</idsDocument>
	</list>		

		
</idsDocument>