<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.1"
			 name="HospitalBillingAccount" udlName="HospitalBillingAccount" domain="Accounts" type="instance"
			 dbTable="hosp_bill_accnt"
	 		 elementOrder="SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
	 		 implementationClass="com.ibi.omni.patient.model.stubs.HospitalBillingAccount"
	 		 excludeFromRamp="true">

	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.1">Removed any references to SourceCode and replaced with SourceCode</change>
	</changeLog>
	
	<customType name="OmniDate" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsDateTimeType"/>
	<customType name="SourceCode" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsCodeType"/>
	
	<documentation>
	Use this Input Specification to feed Guarantor Account information.
	</documentation>
	
	<element name="SourceName" key="true" type="string" dbColumn="source_name">
		<documentation>
		This element must identify the source system that was responsible for generating this 
	    data. This value is determined by the integration team and used in combination with 
	    SourceInstanceId will allow this record to be traced back to its originating source.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="SourceInstanceId" key="true" type="string" dbColumn="src_source_instance_id">
		<documentation>
		This element should contain an integration manufactured value that uniquely identifies the
		collection element and can be used to map back to the source system. Whatever value is
		manufactured must not change over time as it will be used to make updates when data
		changes in the source system.
		
		When processing the IDS the loading system will use the parent document SourceSystem plus
		this SourceInstanceId to find a previously loaded collection element. If a collection element 
		was found then it will be merged, otherwise it will be added to current collection.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="SourceInstanceIdName" type="string" dbColumn="source_instance_id_name">
		<documentation>
		This element gives an indication of where the data came from in the source
	 	system. Used in the 360 viewer for data stewards to trace data.
		</documentation>
	</element>
</idsDocument>
