<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.2.6" changeVersion="1" domain="Financial" type="instance"
			 name="AccountTransaction"  
	 		 elementOrder="TransactionNumber, Account, Remitter, HealthPlanCoverageId, PatientHealthPlan, ServiceLine,
	 		  Location, TransactionTypeCode, TransactionCurrencyCode, PaymentAdjustmentCode, TransactionDateTime,ReplacedDate,
	 		  TransactionAmount, TransactionDescription, CostCenter, RemitterTypeCode"
	 		 implementationClass="com.ibi.omni.patient.model.financial.AccountTransaction">	 					
	  	 					
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.2.6_0">Initial Version</change>
		<change version="1.2.8_0">Deprecated HealthPlanCoverageId and added PatientHealthClaim</change>
		<change version="1.2.8_1">Added SourceStatusCode to instance and collection items.</change>
		<change version="1.2.8_2">GuarantorAccount changed to a reference to Guarantor.</change>
		<change version="1.2.8_3">Added CostCenter.</change>
	</changeLog>
	
	<notes>
	- Should there be a reference to a Claim or a Bill on the Transaction? How else can you determine the balance of a specific bill or claim?
	- Did not implement TransactionQuantity
	- Documentation for AccountTransaction is not accurate. It is broader than that.
	</notes>
	
	<customType name="OmniDate" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsDateTimeType"/>
	<customType name="SourceCode" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsCodeType"/>
	<customType name="OmniLink" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsLinkType"/>
	
	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="ExtendedAttributes, SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
	
	<documentation>	
	Definition TBD
	</documentation>

	<element name="TransactionNumber" type="string">
		<documentation>
		The customer-facing number which identifies the Account Transaction.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>12345678</example>
	</element>

	<element name="Account" type="OmniLink" contains="Account" keys="SourceName, SourceInstanceId" allowCreate="true">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify an Account in the system using the Account's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load Account
		information using this element, however if the Account is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the Account
		when loaded.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<![CDATA[
			<Account>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>AccountId</SourceInstanceId>
			</Account>
			]]>
		</example>		
	</element>

	<element name="Remitter" type="OmniLink" contains="Payer, Patient, Guarantor" keys="SourceName, SourceInstanceId" allowCreate="true">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify a Remitter (Payer, Patient, or Guarantor) in the system using the Remitter's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load Payer, Patient, or 
		Guarantor information using this element, however if the specific entity is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the entity
		when loaded.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<![CDATA[
			<Payer>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>PayerId</SourceInstanceId>
			</Payer>
			]]>
		</example>		
	</element>

	<element name="HealthPlanCoverageId" type="string">
		<documentation>
		deprecated: UNDER CONSTRUCTION: HealthPlanCoverage has not been completed. Add unique HealthPlanCoverageId until this element is changed to a link.
		
		Use this element to specify the HealthPlanCoverage. 
		</documentation>	
	</element>	

  <element name="PatientHealthPlan" type="OmniLink" contains="PatientHealthPlan" keys="SourceName, SourceInstanceId" allowCreate="true">
    <documentation>
        Patient Health Plan record associated with the transaction.  This is maintained in the Payer domain.
        
        Use this element to specify a PatientHealthPlan in the system using the PatientHealthPlan's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load PatientHealthPlan
        information using this element, however if the PatientHealthPlan is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the PatientHealthPlan
        when loaded.
    </documentation>
        
    <example>
        <![CDATA[
        <PatientHealthPlan>
          <SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
          <SourceInstanceId>PatientHealthPlanId</SourceInstanceId>
        </PatientHealthPlan>
        ]]>
    </example>    
  </element>
  
	<element name="ServiceLine" type="OmniLink" contains="OrganizationalUnit" keys="SourceName, SourceInstanceId" allowCreate="true">
		<documentation>
		A single organizational unit, maintained in the Organization domain, will be assigned to each service line. A service line provides the healthcare industry the ability to determine the profitability of its diverse services.  These are typically limited to a handful of well defined, mutually exclusive categories or groupings of individual services or interventions.  They are often associated with the DRG.  A service line can be tied to multiple physical locations (Oncology is provided at Facility1 and Facility2, Orthopedics is provided at Facility2 and Facility3).
		Use this element to specify a ServiceLine in the system using the OrganizationalUnit's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load OrganizationalUnit
		information using this element, however if the OrganizationalUnit is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the OrganizationalUnit
		when loaded.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<![CDATA[
			<OrganizationalUnit>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>ServiceLineId</SourceInstanceId>
			</OrganizationalUnit>
			]]>
		</example>		
	</element>

	<element name="Location" type="OmniLink" contains="FacilityLocation" keys="SourceName, SourceInstanceId" allowCreate="true">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify a FacilityLocation in the system using the FacilityLocation's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load FacilityLocation
		information using this element, however if the FacilityLocation is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the FacilityLocation
		when loaded.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<![CDATA[
			<FacilityLocation>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>FacilityLocationId</SourceInstanceId>
			</FacilityLocation>
			]]>
		</example>		
	</element>

	<element name="TransactionTypeCode" type="SourceCode" codeTable="0017">
		<documentation>
			Code indicating the specific, detailed transaction type from the source system. A source system can have a
			few or hundreds of types of payments and/or adjustments..
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="OMNI" sourceCodeSet="0017" sourceCode="PY"/>
	</element>

	<element name="TransactionCurrencyCode" type="SourceCode" codeTable="4217">
		<documentation>
		The monetary unit in which Amount is denominated.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="OMNI" sourceCodeSet="4217" sourceCode="USD"/>
	</element>

	<element name="PaymentAdjustmentCode" type="SourceCode" codeTable="0468">
		<documentation>
			Code indicating whether this represents a payment or an adjustment.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="OMNI" sourceCodeSet="0468" sourceCode="1"/>
	</element>

	<element name="TransactionDateTime" type="OmniDate">
		<documentation>
		Date and time the transaction was recorded on the account.
		</documentation>
		
		<example format="yyyy-MM-dd hh:mm">2013-01-01 08:00</example>
	</element>

	<element name="ReplacedDate" type="OmniDate">
		<documentation>
			Date and time the transaction was replaced on the account.
		</documentation>
		
		<example format="yyyy-MM-dd hh:mm">2013-01-01 08:00</example>
	</element>

	<element name="TransactionAmount" type="double">
		<documentation>
		Dollar amount of the particular transaction.  This code normally encompasses whether the dollar amount adds to or subtracts from the balance of the account.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="TransactionDescription" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Description of the transaction.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="CostCenter" type="OmniLink" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
			An Organizational Unit representing a specific cost
			center. A Cost Center is a segment of an enterprise for which
			Accounting is performed in the General Ledger.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="RemitterTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
			Generally applies to payments, a coded element that distinguishes between self (patient) pay, guarantor and payers.
			In many source systems all payers, whether they are individuals or insurance companies, are a single codeset.
			These can be mapped directly to this code without change and then harmonized through parent codes.
			Categorization can then be achieved through code maps if desired.
		</documentation>

	</element>
</idsDocument>