<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Survey" type="instance" 
	name="GeneralPurposeSurvey"
	elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, MedicalOrganization, Department, ServiceLine, ServiceLineIdentifier,
				  ServiceLineName, Provider, PatientInformation, EncounterInformation, SurveyInformation">

	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>

	<include name="CommonElements"
		prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
		appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy" />

	<documentation>
		Surveys are used to poll customers on their level of satisfaction with a
		service or product.
		This IDS represents a general purpose survey to use when a there is no
		tailored survey
		(i.e. Patient Satisfaction, Provider Satisfaction, Safety Survey, etc).
	</documentation>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
			Specifies the physical medical facility where the patient received treatment.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
		<documentation>
			If data pertains to a particular location within the facility such as a
			specific
			building, it is defined here.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalOrganization" type="link" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>
			Identifies the medical organization. This organization consists of a group of
			people
			working together to improve methods of health care delivery.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
			Specifies the department (Emergency Room, Neonatal Unit, ICU, Radiology,
			Oncology, etc.)
			within the organization.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ServiceLine" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
			A service line provides the healthcare industry the ability to
			determine the profitability
			of its diverse services. These are typically limited to a handful of
			well defined, mutually exclusive categories
			or groupings of individual services or interventions. They are often
			associated with the DRG (diagnosis related group).
			A service line can be tied to multiple physical locations (Oncology is
			provided at Facility1 and Facility2, Orthopedics
			is provided at Facility2 and Facility3).
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ServiceLineIdentifier" type="string">
		<documentation>
			Identifies a number assigned to represent a specific service line. The
			ServiceLineId
			attribute should be used when the client hasn't implemented the
			OrganizationalUnit defined as
			type Service Line in the Organization IDS.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ServiceLineName" type="string">
		<documentation>
			Identifies a name assigned to represent a specific service line. The
			ServiceLineName
			attribute should be used when the client hasn't implemented the
			OrganizationalUnit defined as
			type Service Line in the Organization IDS.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="Provider" type="link" contains="Provider">
		<documentation>
			Represents data about the individual who provided health care services during
			the encounter.
			The provider may or may not be relevant to this survey.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<group name="PatientInformation" elementOrder="Patient, Gender, Race, AgeAtArrival, AgeAtArrivalUnitCode" dbColumnPrefix="pat">

		<documentation>
			Patient is a group of attributes containing patient specific information
			gathered at the
			time of the encounter. This data may or may not be relevant to this
			survey.
		</documentation>

		<element name="Patient" type="link" contains="Patient">
			<documentation>
				Patient represents data about the individual who received health care
				services during the encounter.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="Gender" type="code" codeTable="0001">
			<documentation>
				Contains the patient's gender documented at the time of the encounter.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="Race" type="code" codeTable="0005">
			<documentation>
				Contains the patient's race documented at the time of the encounter.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AgeAtArrival" type="integer">
			<documentation>
				Contains the patient's age when arrived for the encounter.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AgeAtArrivalUnitCode" type="code" codeTable="6025">
			<documentation>
				Contains the units in which the patient's age at arrival was documented.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="EncounterInformation"
		elementOrder="Encounter, EncounterTypeCode, AdmissionDateTime, DischargeDateTime, PrincipalDiagnosisCode, LengthOfStay " dbColumnPrefix="enc" >

		<documentation>
			Encounter is a group of attributes containing details pertaining to the
			patient's visit
			and health care services received. This data may or may not be relevant
			to this survey.
		</documentation>

		<element name="Encounter" type="link" contains="Encounter">
			<documentation>
				An Encounter is a specific instance of a patient coming in contact
				with one or more
				health care providers for the purpose of receiving health care services.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="EncounterTypeCode" type="code" codeTable="6000">
			<documentation>
				Describes the type of interaction between a patient and healthcare
				participants for
				the purpose of providing patient services or assessing the health
				status of a patient.
				The encounter type value may be different than the initial type
				assigned to the encounter if it changed over time.

				Ambulatory: A comprehensive term for health care provided in a healthcare
				facility on a nonresident basis.
				The term ambulatory usually implies that the patient has come to the
				location and is not assigned to a bed.
				Sometimes referred to as an outpatient encounter.

				Emergency: A patient encounter that takes place at a dedicated healthcare
				service delivery location where
				the patient receives immediate evaluation and treatment, provided until
				the patient can be discharged or
				responsibility for the patient's care is transferred elsewhere (for example, the
				patient could be admitted
				as an inpatient or transferred to another facility).

				Field: A patient encounter that takes place both outside a dedicated
				service delivery location and outside
				a patient's residence (for example, traffic accident).
				Home Health: Healthcare encounter that takes place in the residence of
				the patient or a designee
				(including physical therapy).

				Inpatient Acute: A patient encounter where a patient is admitted by a
				hospital or equivalent facility,
				assigned to a location where patients generally stay at least overnight and
				provided with room, board,
				and continuous nursing service. Acute conditions are severe and sudden
				in onset such as a heart attack.

				Inpatient Non-Acute: A patient encounter where a patient is admitted by a
				hospital or equivalent facility,
				assigned to a location where patients generally stay at least overnight and
				provided with room, board,
				and continuous nursing service. Non-acute, or chronic, conditions have
				a long-developing syndrome,
				such as osteoporosis or asthma.

				Pre-Admission: A patient encounter where patient is scheduled or planned to
				receive service delivery
				in the future, and the patient is given a pre-admission account
				number. When the patient comes back for
				subsequent service, the pre-admission encounter is selected and is
				encapsulated into the service registration,
				and a new account number is generated. Usage Note: This is intended to
				be used in advance of encounter types
				such as ambulatory, inpatient encounter, virtual, etc.

				Short Stay: An encounter where the patient is admitted to a health care
				facility for a predetermined
				length of time, usually less than 24 hours.

				Virtual: A patient encounter where the patient and the practitioner(s) are
				not in the same physical location.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AdmissionDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Date and time the patient was admitted into the facility.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="DischargeDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Date and time the patient was discharged into the facility.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="PrincipalDiagnosisCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
				Depicts the principal diagnosed condition based on the standardized
				diagnosis
				code value set used in the health system (ICD-9, ICD-10).
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="LengthOfStay" type="integer">
			<documentation>
				Length of stay of inpatient for an encounter, represented in days. General
				calculation
				is the number of days from the Admission Date to the Discharge Date on
				an Inpatient encounter. Each customer
				may calculate this value based on different set of criteria. For
				example, a customer may or may not truncate
				the time portion of the Admission Date and Discharge Date which can
				change the result by an entire day.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	</group>

	<element name="SurveyInformation" type="link" contains="Survey">
		<documentation>
			Captures specific attributes for the focus and identification of the survey,
			the approved
			vendor that administered the survey, when it was taken, and the list of
			questions and answers provided by
			the person who filled out the survey.
		</documentation>
	</element>
</idsDocument>



			
		

	
