<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Clinical" type="instance"
			 name="DailyEmergency"  
	 		 elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, Department, PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, ReportingDate, EmergencyStats,
					EDVisits"
			 >
	 		               	
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>
	

	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>

	<notes> 

	</notes>
			
	<documentation>
	Daily Emergency enables the customer to populate the Actual, Projected, Budget or Benchmark totals by facility, 
	location or department for a particular date.  It includes aggregated emergency department visit statistics tracking 
	counts of visits, patients admitted, average minutes spent processing patients from arrival, triage, bed assignment 
	and deciding whether to admit.  For individual visits, it allows capturing the time patient arrives, is triaged, 
	assigned to a bed, if admitted and when, disposition assigned and time departs.
	</documentation>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the physical medical facility where the patient received treatment.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<Facility>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
			</Facility>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
		<documentation>
		If data pertains to a particular location within the facility such as a specific building, nurse unit, 
		floor or ward, it is defined here.
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<FacilityLocation>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Hospital floor 3</SourceInstanceId>
			</FacilityLocation>
		</example>			
	</element>

	<element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the department (Emergency Room, Neonatal Unit, ICU, Radiology, Oncology, etc.) within the organization.
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<OrganizationalUnit>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Emergency Room</SourceInstanceId>
			</OrganizationalUnit>
		</example>			
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for any metric for the reporting date.  
		A single IDS can be for only one Planning Category/Subcategory combination. If the customer reports this at the 
		departmental level, then each IDS represents one Department/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can 
		generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's down to the departmental 
		level, or anything and everything in between. 

		The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, but how the customer 
		uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making comparisons.  Actuals would capture the real 
		statistics for the reporting date.
		
		If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula for a hospital or 
		department of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for different percentiles, if they exist or are 
		calculable.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCodes">
		Projected
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks IDS's for different 
		percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">
		50th percentile
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="ReportingDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Represents the reporting period. This IDS tracks metrics for a single given date only.
		</documentation>
			
		<example>
			<ReportingDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-01-01
			</ReportingDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<group name="EmergencyStats" elementOrder="TotalIEDVisits, EDPatientsAdmitted, AverageArrivalToDepartureTime, AverageDecisionToAdmitTime, 
												AverageArrivalToTriageTime, AverageTriageToBedTime">
		<documentation>
		EmergencyStats is a group of aggregated emergency department visit metrics at the facility for the reporting date.
		</documentation>

		<element name="TotalIEDVisits" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Total number of emergency department visits at the facility for the reporting date.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<TotalIEDVisits>
					12
				</TotalIEDVisits>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="EDPatientsAdmitted" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			Total number of emergency department visits that resulted in patients being admitted at the facility for the reporting date.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<EDPatientsAdmitted>
					12
				</EDPatientsAdmitted>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="AverageArrivalToDepartureTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The average time, in minutes, it takes for ED arrival time to ED departure times for ED admits at the facility for the reporting date.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<AverageArrivalToDepartureTime>
					15
				</AverageArrivalToDepartureTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="AverageDecisionToAdmitTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<AverageDecisionToAdmitTime>
					15
				</AverageDecisionToAdmitTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="AverageArrivalToTriageTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The average time, in minutes, it takes for ED arrival time to ED Triage times for ED admits at the facility for the reporting date.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<AverageArrivalToTriageTime>
					15
				</AverageArrivalToTriageTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="AverageTriageToBedTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The average time, in minutes, it takes for ED Triage time to ED Room time for ED admits at the facility for the reporting date.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<AverageTriageToBedTime>
					15
				</AverageTriageToBedTime>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>
	
	<list name="EDVisits">
		<documentation>
		EDVisits is a collection of EDVisit instances which track the various times of the emergency department visit such as when arrived, 
		triaged, assigned to a bed, departed, etc., at the facility for the reporting date.
		</documentation>
		
		<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Clinical" type="instance_child"
			 name="EDVisit"  
	 		 elementOrder="ArrivalTime, TriageTime, EDBedTime, AdmitTime, AdmitDecisionTime, EDDepartTime,  EDDispositionCode, AdmittedIndicator"
			 >
		<include name="CommonElements"
				 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
				 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/> 		               	
		<changeLog>
			<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
		</changeLog>
	
		<notes> 
		</notes>
				
		<documentation>
		Tracks the various times of the emergency department visit such as when arrived, triaged, assigned to a bed, departed, etc., 
		at the facility for the reporting date.
		</documentation>
		
		<element name="ArrivalTime" type="time">
			<documentation>
			Tracks the time on the reporting date the patient arrived in the emergency department.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<ArrivalTime format="hh:mm">
					12:10
				</ArrivalTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="TriageTime" type="time">
			<documentation>
			Tracks the time on the reporting date the triage process is started for a patient in the emergency department.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TriageTime format="hh:mm">
					12:10
				</TriageTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="EDBedTime" type="time">
			<documentation>
			Tracks the time on the reporting date the patient is assigned to a bed in the emergency department.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<EDBedTime format="hh:mm">
					12:10
				</EDBedTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="AdmitTime" type="time">
			<documentation>
			For a patient in the emergency department, tracks the time on the reporting date when the patient was admitted.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<AdmitTime format="hh:mm">
					12:10
				</AdmitTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="AdmitDecisionTime" type="time">
			<documentation>
			For a patient in the emergency department, tracks the time on the reporting date when it was decided to admit the patient.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<AdmitDecisionTime format="hh:mm">
					12:10
				</AdmitDecisionTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="EDDepartTime" type="time">
			<documentation>
			Tracks the time on the reporting date when the patient left the emergency department.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<EDDepartTime format="hh:mm">
					12:10
				</EDDepartTime>
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="EDDispositionCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the reason the patient is discharged from the emergency department.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="HL7 Value Set" codeSet="0112">
			Routine Discharge
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<element name="AdmittedIndicator" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether patient was admitted during this emergency department visit.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="HL7 v2 Tables" codeSet="0136">
			Y = Yes
			</example>
		</element>	
	</idsDocument>
	</list>	
</idsDocument>