<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Clinical" type="instance"
			 name="SurgeryCase"  
	 		 elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalOrganization, Department, ServiceLine, ServiceLineId, ServiceLineName, 
					Patient, Encounter, CaseId, CaseDescription, CaseStatusCode, CaseLevelCode, ASAClassCode, SurgicalSpecialtyCode, PurposeCode,
					OperatingRoomShiftCode, PreOpDiagnosis, PreOpDiagnosisText, PostOpDiagnosis, PostOpDiagnosisText,
					ScheduledAnesthesiaTypeCode, ActualAnesthesiaTypeCode, WoundClassCode, Scheduled, Actual, CancelDateTime,
					CancelReasonCode, CancelText, DelayReasonCode, DelayText">
	 		               	
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>

	<customType name="SourceCode" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsCodeType"/>

	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
			
	<documentation>
	When a patient needs surgery, a surgery case can be defined that tracks where the surgeries will be performed, 
	associated encounter, surgical specialty required, class of patient, condition of patient before and after all 
	procedures, all participating providers and tracking point-in-time activities during each phase (ORPrep, PreOp, 
	Operative, PostOp, ORCleanUp).  Additionally, scheduled and actual statistics will be captured for anesthesia, 
	locations to perform surgery, surgery and cleanup durations, and who will participate in the surgical case. 
	</documentation>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the physical medical facility where the patient received treatment.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalOrganization" type="link" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the medical organization. This organization consists of a group of people working together 
		to improve methods of health care delivery.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="Department" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the department (Emergency Room, Neonatal Unit, ICU, Radiology, Oncology, etc.) within the organization.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="ServiceLine" type="link" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
		A service line provides the healthcare industry the ability to determine the profitability of its diverse services.  
		These are typically limited to a handful of well defined, mutually exclusive categories or groupings of individual 
		services or interventions.  They are often associated with the DRG (diagnosis related group).  A service line can 
		be tied to multiple physical locations (Oncology is provided at Facility1 and Facility2, Orthopedics is provided 
		at Facility2 and Facility3). 
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ServiceLineId" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies a number assigned to represent a specific service line.  The ServiceLineId attribute should be used 
		when the client hasn't implemented the OrganizationalUnit defined as type Service Line in the Organization IDS.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ServiceLineName" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies a name assigned to represent a specific service line.  The ServiceLineName attribute should be used 
		when the client hasn't implemented the OrganizationalUnit defined as type Service Line in the Organization IDS.
		</documentation>
	</element>	

	<element name="Patient" type="link" contains="Patient">
		<documentation>
		Patient represents data about the individual who received health care services during the encounter.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="Encounter" type="link" contains="Encounter">
		<documentation>
		An Encounter is a specific instance of a patient coming in contact with one or more health care providers 
		for the purpose of receiving health care services.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="CaseId" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains the identifier for this surgery case.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="CaseDescription" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains the description for this surgery case.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="CaseStatusCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		A surgery case may contain more than one surgical procedure.  This attribute identifies the status 
		assigned to the overall case.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="CaseLevelCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		The grouping of cases into levels can be used to reflect acuity of procedures performed with staff involvement 
		and resources required. For example, a small hospital with minor surgical procedures can be case levels 1 to 3 while a 
		large hospital with a full spectrum of surgical procedures can be case levels 1 to 6. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ASAClassCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		The American Society of Anesthesiologists' (ASA) physical status classification serves as guide to better 
		communication among anesthesiologists about clinical conditions of patients prior to surgery.  The higher 
		the ASA class, the higher the risk.  For emergency surgery, "E" is appended to the ASA class (e.g., 1E represents 
		emergency surgery on a healthy patient). 
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="SurgicalSpecialtyCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the specialization required of the primary provider overseeing this surgery case.

		ASC X12N Health Care Provider Taxonomy, Level 3 - Area of Specialization (see Code Sets TAB)
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PurposeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		The reason the surgery is being performed. Exploratory surgery is performed to aid or confirm a diagnosis. Therapeutic surgery treats a previously diagnosed condition. Preventative surgery is performed to prevent a future condition from occurring.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="OperatingRoomShiftCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the shift when the surgery was performed.  Shifts for a 24-hour period can be split in three 8-hour 
		shifts such as First, Second and Third Shifts.  Optionally, there can be any number of shifts such as Early Morning, 
		Mid Morning, Late Morning, Noon, Early Afternoon, Mid Afternoon, Late Afternoon, Early Evening, Mid Evening, 
		Late Evening and Midnight.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PreOpDiagnosis" type="link" contains="DiagnosisEvent">
		<documentation>
		This Diagnosis Event captures details on the patient's diagnosed condition prior to any surgery.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PreOpDiagnosisText" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains additional text on the patient's diagnosed condition prior to any surgery.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PostOpDiagnosis" type="link" contains="DiagnosisEvent">
		<documentation>
		This Diagnosis Event captures details on the patient's diagnosed condition after all surgical procedures have been performed.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PostOpDiagnosisText" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains additional text on the patient's diagnosed condition after all surgical procedures have been performed.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ScheduledAnesthesiaTypeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		There are different types of anesthesia and the determination of which to use depends on the type of surgery 
		and medical condition of the patient. This scheduled type of anesthesia is the preferred method.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ActualAnesthesiaTypeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		This contains the actual type of anesthesia used during surgery.  If there were multiple surgical procedues, 
		use the anesthesia administered during the primary surgical procedure. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="WoundClassCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Contains the classification of surgical wounds.  If there were multiple surgical procedues, use the value that 
		best describes the condition of the wound after the patient's last procedure.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<group name="Scheduled" elementOrder="StartDateTime, EndDateTime, Duration, ProcedureStartDateTime, ProcedureEndDateTime,
	ProcedureDuration, SetupStartDateTime, SetupEndDateTime, SetupDuration, CleanupStartDateTime, CleanupEndDateTime,
	CleanupDuration, TurnoverDuration, SurgicalArea, OperatingRoom, ScheduledIndicator, PriorityCode, SlotTypeCode, Quantity">
		<documentation>
		Scheduled is a group of attributes tracking when, where and durations expected as pertains to this patient's surgery case.
		</documentation>

		<element name="StartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the date and time when the surgical case was scheduled to start.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	
		<element name="EndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the date and time when the surgical case was scheduled to end.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="Duration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled case duration, which is generally the time between the scheduled start and end of the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="ProcedureStartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled date and time of the start of the first surgical procedure in the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="ProcedureEndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled date and time of the end of the last surgical procedure in the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="ProcedureDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Contains the total scheduled duration of the surgical procedures in the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SetupStartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled date and time of the start of the preparation of the operating room for the surgical case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SetupEndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled date and time of the end of the preparation of the operating room for the surgical case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SetupDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled time, in minutes, to prepare the operating room before the entire surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="CleanupStartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled date and time of the start of work to clean and sanitize the operating room after surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="CleanupEndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the scheduled date and time of the end of work to clean and sanitize the operating room after surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="CleanupDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Contains the scheduled time, in minutes, to clean and sanitize the operating room after the entire surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="TurnoverDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Also called Turnaround time, it generally refers to the scheduled time between one patient leaving the
				operating room and the next patient entering. Usually this is meant to exclude any scheduled gaps
				between cases. Different hospitals may define this interval differently.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SurgicalArea" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the scheduled location within the facility that represents the Surgical Area.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="OperatingRoom" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the scheduled location within the facility that represents the Operating Room where the surgery 
			is to be performed.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="ScheduledIndicator" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether surgery for this patient has been scheduled.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="PriorityCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Contains the urgency with which to schedule this patient's surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SlotTypeCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Surgeries can be scheduled to occur in a specific slot of time.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="Quantity" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Scheduled quantity associated with this case, if any.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Actual" elementOrder="StartDateTime, EndDateTime, Duration, ProcedureStartDateTime, ProcedureEndDateTime,
	ProcedureDuration, SetupStartDateTime, SetupEndDateTime, SetupDuration, CleanupStartDateTime, CleanupEndDateTime,
	CleanupDuration, TurnoverDuration, SurgicalArea, OperatingRoom, SlotTypeCode, Quantity">
		<documentation>
		Actual is a group of attributes tracking what actually did take place and where during this patient's surgery case.
		</documentation>

		<element name="StartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the date and time when the surgical case actually started.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	
		<element name="EndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the date and time when the surgical case actually ended.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="Duration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual case duration, which is generally the time between the actual start and end of the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="ProcedureStartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual date and time of the start of the first surgical procedure in the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="ProcedureEndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual date and time of the end of the last surgical procedure in the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="ProcedureDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Contains the total actual duration of the surgical procedures in the case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SetupStartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual date and time of the start of the preparation of the operating room for the surgical case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SetupEndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual date and time of the end of the preparation of the operating room for the surgical case.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SetupDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual time, in minutes, to prepare the operating room before the entire surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="CleanupStartDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual date and time of the start of work to clean and sanitize the operating room after surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="CleanupEndDateTime" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
				Contains the actual date and time of the end of work to clean and sanitize the operating room after surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="CleanupDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Contains the actual time, in minutes, to clean and sanitize the operating room after the entire surgery.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="TurnoverDuration" type="double">
			<documentation>
				Also called Turnaround time, it generally refers to the actual time between one patient leaving the
				operating room and the next patient entering. Usually this is meant to exclude any scheduled gaps
				between cases. Different hospitals may define this interval differently.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SurgicalArea" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the actual location within the facility that represents the Surgical Area.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="OperatingRoom" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the actual location within the facility that represents the Operating Room where the surgery was performed.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SlotTypeCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Contains the actual slot of time when the surgery was performed.
			</documentation>
		</element>		

		<element name="Quantity" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Actual quantity associated with this case, if any.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	</group>

	<element name="CancelDateTime" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the date and time when the surgery case was cancelled.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="CancelReasonCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the reason the patient's surgery case was cancelled.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="CancelText" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains additional text on why the patient's surgery case was cancelled.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="DelayReasonCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
			Specifies the reason the patient's surgery case was delayed.
		</documentation>

	</element>

	<element name="DelayText" type="string">
		<documentation>
			Contains additional text on why the patient's surgery case was delayed.
		</documentation>
	</element>

</idsDocument>
