<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.2.1" changeVersion="3" domain="Accessibility" type="instance"
			 name="PatientWaitList"  
	 		 elementOrder="Patient, Referral, ScheduledAppointment, WaitListStatusCode, RemovalReasonCode, VisitTypeCode,
	 		               TreatmentCode, PriorityCode, AppointmentLength, SchedulingPreference, PreferedBeginDate,
	 		               PreferedEndDate, AppointmentPreferences">
	  	 					
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.2.1">Initial Version</change>
		<change version="1.2.1_2">Replaced ReferralId and ScheduledAppointmentId with real links</change>
		<change version="1.2.1_3">Added SourceStatusCode to instance and collection items.</change>		
	</changeLog>
		
	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="ExtendedAttributes, SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
	
	<documentation>
	Use this document to load Patients that are waiting to be scheduled for appointments. This document can track where the
	Patient was referred from, type of visit needed, priority and status of the appointment.
	</documentation>

	<element name="Patient" type="link" contains="Patient">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the Patient waiting using the Patient's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load Patient
		information using this element, however if the Patient is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the 
		Patient when loaded.
		</documentation>
	</element>
		
	<element name="Referral" type="link" contains="ReferralSource" dbColumn="referral_id">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the Referal that prompted the request for the appointment. 
		</documentation>
	</element>	
		
	<element name="ScheduledAppointment" type="link" contains="Appointment" dbColumn="appointment_id">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to link this PatientWaitList to a scheduled appointment.  
		</documentation>	
	</element>	

  	<element name="WaitListStatusCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the status of this PatientWaitList. For example:
		Pending, Scheduled, Deleted, Expired, Auto-Deleted, etc...
		</documentation>
	</element>

  	<element name="RemovalReasonCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		When a wait list item no longer requires scheduling use this element to specify the reason. 
		
		For Example:
		Regular Treatment, Emergency Admission, Deceased, Treated Elsewhere, Complaint Disappeared, Indication Expired,
		Patient Request, Order Expired, Referral Expired, etc...
		</documentation>
	</element>

  	<element name="VisitTypeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the type of visit being requested.
		</documentation>
	</element>

  	<element name="TreatmentCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the type treatment required during the appointment. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

  	<element name="PriorityCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the priority of the appointment request. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="AppointmentLength" type="integer">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the length of appointment requested. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

  	<element name="SchedulingPreference" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the Patient's preference for scheduling the appointment. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

  	<element name="PreferedBeginDate" type="date">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the first date to look for an appointment. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

  	<element name="PreferedEndDate" type="date">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the last date to look for an appointment. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<list name="AppointmentPreferences">
		<documentation>
		Use this collection to specify the list of preferred Locations and/or Providers. This list can be
		validated against ProviderAvailablitySlots to held scheduling and appointment.  
		</documentation>
		
		<idsDocument name="PatientWaitListPreference" type="instance_child"
			 		 		elementOrder="Provider, Location">
			 		
			<include name="CommonElements"
					 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
					 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
					 	  	
			<documentation>
			Use this document to specify a preferred FacilityLocation and/or Provider combination to use when
			scheduling an appointment. 
			</documentation>
		
			<element name="Provider" type="link" contains="Provider">
				<documentation>
				Use this element to specify a preferred service Provider using the Provider's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load Provider
				information using this element, however if the Provider is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the Provider
				when loaded.
				</documentation>
			</element>
				
			<element name="Location" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation" dbColumn="facility_location_id">
				<documentation>
				Use this element to specify the preferred location to perform services using the FacilityLocation's SourceName and SourceInstanceId.
				You cannot load FacilityLocation using this element, however if the FacilityLocation is not found a "placeholder" will be created that will
				contain the FacilityLocation information when its loaded.
				</documentation>
			</element>
		</idsDocument>			
	</list>

</idsDocument>
