<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.2.1" changeVersion="2" domain="Accessibility" type="instance"
			 name="ProviderAvailabilitySlot"  
	 		 elementOrder="Provider, Location, SlotBeginDateTime, SlotLength, NumberOfAppointmentsScheduled, OriginalOpeningsPerSlot,
	 		               OriginalNumberOfOverbooksAllowed, PrivateSlotIndicator, UnavailableIndicator, UnavailableReasonCode, HeldIndicator,
	 		               HeldReasonCode, BlockedIndicator, BlockedReasonCode, Appointments">
	  	 					
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.2.1">Initial Version</change>
		<change version="1.2.1_2">Added SourceStatusCode to instance and collection items.</change>		
	</changeLog>
	
	<notes>
	BlockedIndicator and BlockedReasonCode replace ProviderAvailabilityBlock since the actual data does not show any
	instances of multiple blocks for the same location. I believe this is an Epic'ism that should not be carried into
	the Omni model.
	</notes>
		
	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="ExtendedAttributes, SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
	
	<documentation>
	The collection of ProviderAvailabilitySlot's can be used to determine Provider utilization. It involves tracking details on slots of time
	used for scheduling appointments. Details for each Provider, Location, and Slot must to loaded using this document, including Patient links
	or unavailable or on hold information.
	</documentation>

	<element name="Provider" type="link" contains="Provider">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify a Provider in the system using the Provider's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load Provider
		information using this element, however if the Provider is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the Provider
		when loaded.
		</documentation>
	</element>
		
	<element name="Location" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation" dbColumn="facility_location_id">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the location that the Provider will perform services using the FacilityLocation's SourceName and SourceInstanceId.
		You cannot load FacilityLocation using this element, however if the FacilityLocation is not found a "placeholder" will be created that will
		contain the FacilityLocation information when its loaded.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="SlotBeginDateTime" type="datetime" dbColumn="slot_begin_date">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the slot date and starting time of the slot.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="SlotLength" type="integer">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the slot duration in minutes.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="NumberOfAppointmentsScheduled" type="integer" dbColumn="nbr_scheduled_appointments">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the total number of appointments that have been scheduled
		against this slot. 
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="OriginalOpeningsPerSlot" type="integer" dbColumn="orig_openings_per_slot">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the number of openings for this slot. This is most likely
		tied to the ProviderTemplateSchedule.OpeningsPerSlot.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="OriginalNumberOfOverbooksAllowed" type="integer" dbColumn="orig_nbr_overbooks_allowed">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the number of overbookings allowed for this slot. 
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="PrivateSlotIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="private_slot_code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify that the slot private or not. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="UnavailableIndicator" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify if the slot was unavailable. For some systems a slot may
		be unavailable due to the entire day being unavailable or a time frame that includes
		this time slot being unavailable. Use UnavailableReasonCode to code the reason for
		the slot unavailability. 
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="UnavailableReasonCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		If the slot was unavailable then use this element to specify the coded reason for
		the unavailability. For example a "V" may indicate the Provider was on vacation.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="HeldIndicator" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify if the slot was held. For some systems a slot may
		be unavailable due to the entire day being held or a time frame that includes
		this time slot being held. Use HeldReasonCode to code the reason for
		the slot unavailability. 
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="HeldReasonCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		If the slot was held then use this element to specify the coded reason for
		the unavailability. For example a "V" may indicate the Provider was on vacation.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="BlockedIndicator" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify if the slot was blocked. Use BlockedReasonCode to 
		code the reason for the slot being blocked. 
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="BlockedReasonCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		If the slot was blocked then use this element to specify the coded reason for
		the unavailability. For example a "Urgent" may indicate the slot is blocked for
		and Urgent Follow Up appointment.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<list name="Appointments">
		<documentation>
		Use this collection to specify the list of Appointments that have been associated with this available slot. 
		Appointments will not sent with this document, this collection will contain links to the appointments.	
		</documentation>
		
		<idsDocument name="ProviderAvailabilityAppointment" type="instance_child" tableName="provider_availability_appt"
			 		 		elementOrder="Appointment">
			 		
			<include name="CommonElements"
					 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
					 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
					 	  	
			<documentation>
			Use this element to link a ProviderAppointment's to ProviderAvailabilitySlot.
			</documentation>
						
			<element name="Appointment" type="link" contains="Appointment">
				<documentation>
				Use this element to specify the appointment that the Provider performed services. 
				</documentation>
			</element>						
		</idsDocument>
	</list>

</idsDocument>
