<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.2.1" changeVersion="2" domain="Accessibility" type="instance"
			 name="ProviderTemplateSchedule"  
	 		 elementOrder="Template, ScheduleStartDate, ScheduleEndDate, DayOfWeek, StartTime, EndTime,
	 		               SlotLength, OpeningsPerSlot, NumberOfOverbooksAllowed, PrivateSlot, ModificationReason">
	  	 					
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.2.1">Initial Version</change>
		<change version="1.2.1_2">Added SourceStatusCode to instance and collection items.</change>
	</changeLog>
		
	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="ExtendedAttributes, SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
	
	<documentation>
	Use this input specification  to load a collection of records supplied by a Provider to define slots of time set aside
	by the Provider at a specific Location that can be used for scheduling appointments. Each ProviderTemplateSchedule can
	provide information for a Provider, Location, Day of Week, Time, and Slot Length. These slots can then be used for 
	determining Provider availability and hence appointment scheduling. 
	</documentation>

	<element name="Template" type="link" contains="ProviderTemplate" dbColumn="provider_template_id">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to link this ProviderTemplateSchedule to a ProviderTemplate using the ProviderTemplate's 
		SourceName and SourceInstanceId.You cannot load ProviderTemplate information using this element, however 
		if the ProviderTemplate is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the ProviderTemplate
		when loaded.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ScheduleStartDate" type="date">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the schedules start date for a Provider at a Location for
		specific day of week and time frame.
		
		Integration Note: Only specify the date format. Any time information should be placed in
		StartTime and EndTime elements.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ScheduleEndDate" type="date">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the schedules end date for a Provider at a Location for
		specific day of week and time frame.
		
		Integration Note: Only specify the date format. Any time information should be placed in
		StartTime and EndTime elements.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="DayOfWeek" type="integer">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the day of week associated with the ProviderTemplateSchedule. This
		is a number starting with 0 for designating Sunday.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="StartTime" type="time" dbColumn="start_time">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the starting time of this TemplateSchedule on the specified day.
		
		Integration Notes: See the java SimpleDateFormat for formatting options.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="EndTime" type="time" dbColumn="end_time">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the ending time of this TemplateSchedule on the specified day.
		
		Integration Notes: See the java SimpleDateFormat for formatting options.		
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="SlotLength" type="integer">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the slot length for the specified DayOfWeek and StartTime-EndTime
		range. All lengths should be in minutes.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="OpeningsPerSlot" type="integer">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the number of openings allowed for each slot. For example a Provider
		may allow 2 Patients to be booked into a 30 minute slot.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="NumberOfOverbooksAllowed" type="integer" dbColumn="nbr_overbooks_allowed">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify the maximum number of overbookings for a slot.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="PrivateSlot" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to specify if the slots for this schedule are private. Typically private slots
		should not be visible to the public as the Patient's may have high visibility. The assumption is
		the when set to "Y" then only private Patients will be scheduled into this slot.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="ModificationReason" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Use this element to code the reason this template was modified. This information along
		with SourceModifiedDay and SourceModifiedBy will give a full audit trail of changes to
		this template.
		</documentation>
	</element>
</idsDocument>
