<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Workforce" type="instance"
			 name="WorkerTraining"  
	 		 elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalOrganization, CostCenter, AccountCode, 
					AccountName, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate, PeriodTypeCode,
					PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, CurrencyCode,
					Worker, TrainingRequirements, TrainingCoursesTaken"
			 >
	 		               	
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>

	<customType name="SourceCode" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsCodeType"/>
	<customType name="OmniLink" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsLinkType"/>

	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>

	<notes> 
	</notes>
			
	<documentation>
 	Continued education is required for many medical professionals to keep their license and/or certification current. 
 	This Worker Training IDS enables the customer to populate the Actual, Projected, Budget or Benchmark statistics on training 
	requirements and courses taken by a worker for a reporting period. 
	</documentation>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="OmniLink" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the physical medical facility associated with the worker.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<Facility>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
			</Facility>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalOrganization" type="OmniLink" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the medical organization associated with the worker.  
		This organization consists of a group of people working together to improve methods 
		of health care delivery.
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<Organization>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Medical Center</SourceInstanceId>
			</Organization>
		</example>
			
	</element>

	<element name="CostCenter" type="OmniLink" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
		An Organizational Unit is a specific group or entity for organizing or managing 
		resources within the enterprise.  Usually, these are made up of people or locations which cooperate 
		in specified objectives.  These may be Departments, Divisions, Nursing Units, Service Lines, Regions,
		 Cost Centers, etc.  A G/L Cost Center is a segment of an enterprise for which Accounting is performed 
		in the General Ledger.  G/L Cost Centers are arranged into a hierarchy which allows roll-ups and 
		drill-downs on financial information within the enterprise.  Low-level Cost Centers may be 
		Nursing Units if the hierarchy is based on physical location, or may be Service Specialty 
		if the hierarchy is based on Service Line.  Use this attribute to link to the Cost Center 
		associated with the workers benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<OrganizationalUnit>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Accounting Department</SourceInstanceId>
			</OrganizationalUnit>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="AccountCode" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the code assigned to the account associated with the worker's training.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<AccountCode>
				4589
			</AccountCode>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="AccountName" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the name assigned to the account associated with the worker's training.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<AccountName>
				JohnDoeAccountName
			</AccountName>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the starting date associated with the worker's training.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodStartDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-03-03
			</PeriodStartDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the ending date associated with the worker's training.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodEndDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-04-04
			</PeriodEndDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the period of time as it pertains to the worker's training.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PeriodTypeCodes">
			Year
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for 
		any metric for the reporting period. A single IDS can be for only one Planning 			
		Category/Subcategory combination. If the customer reports this at the facility level, 
		then each IDS represents one Facility/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can 
		generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's 
		down to the cost center level, or anything and everything in between. 

		The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, 
		but how the customer uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making 
		comparisons. Actuals would capture the real statistics for the reporting period.

		If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula 
		for a hospital or organization of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for 
		different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the beginning of the 
		fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCode">
			Projected
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or 
		Benchmarks IDS's for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">
			50th percentile
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="CurrencyCode" type="SourceCode" codeSource="OMNI" codeSet="4217">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the denomination for all amounts using the industry standard defined in
		the ISO 4217 code set.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="Worker" type="OmniLink" contains="Worker">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the worker receiving the training reported during this period.  A Worker is member
 		of the Workforce, such as an Employee, Contingent Worker (e.g. Independent Professionals, 
		Temporary Contract Workers, Independent Contractors, Consultants), or other Person of Interest 
		(e.g. External Instructor, External Trainee, Global Payroll, Stock - Board Member, Stock - Non-HR Employee).
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<Worker>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Consultants</SourceInstanceId>
			</Worker>
		</example>
			
	</element>

	<list name="TrainingRequirements">
		<documentation>
		TrainingRequirements is a collection of TrainingRequirement instances.  Medical professionals 
		maintain their competency in their field through continuing education as well as to learn about new and developing 
		areas in their specialty.  These training requirements may take place in-person, written publications, online programs, 
		audio, video or other electronic media. Content for these programs is developed, reviewed and delivered by experts
		in their individual clinical areas.  Training that is required by medical professionals, such as to maintain 
		their license, is defined here.
		</documentation>
	
	<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Workforce" type="instance_child"
				 name="TrainingRequirement"  
		 		 elementOrder="RequirementSource, TrainingGoal, RequiredAmount, AmountAchieved,
						TrainingCreditTypeCode, RequirementPeriodTypeCode"
				 >
		<include name="CommonElements"
				 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
				 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
			               	
		<changeLog>
			<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
		</changeLog>
		
	
		
	
		<notes> 
		</notes>
				
		<documentation>
	 	Medical professionals maintain their competency in their field through continuing 
		education as well as to learn about new and developing areas in their specialty.  
		These training requirements may take place in-person, written publications, 
		online programs, audio, video or other electronic media. Content for these programs is 
		developed, reviewed and delivered by experts in their individual clinical areas.  
		Training that is required by medical professionals, such as to maintain their license, is defined here.
		</documentation>
		
		<element name="RequirementSource" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Contains the name of the entity, such as a state or medical association, 
			that requires a specific form of education to ensure those in the medical 
			field maintain competence and learn about new or developing areas in their field.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<RequirementSource>
					NY State
				</RequirementSource>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingGoal" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the reason for obtaining this training such as accreditation or to maintain their license.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingGoal>
					Maintain License
				</TrainingGoal>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="RequiredAmount" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the number of training credits (e.g. hours, CME units, CEU) required to complete the training.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<RequiredAmount>
					12
				</RequiredAmount>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="AmountAchieved" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the number of training credits that have been completed.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<AmountAchieved>
					4
				</AmountAchieved>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingCreditTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
			<documentation>
			Defines the measure used in continuing education programs such as hours, 
			continuing medical education (CME) units, continuing education units (CEU) 
			or credit hours.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="TrainingCreditTypeCodes">
				Hours
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="RequirementPeriodTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
			<documentation>
			Identifies how often this training must be retaken as a requirement for maintaining
	 		license or certification.  For example, Arizona requires an average of 40 hours of CME every 
			two years for medical professionals to maintain their licenses.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="RequirementPeriodTypeCodes">
				Year
			</example>
		</element>
	</idsDocument>	
	</list>

	<list name="TrainingCoursesTaken">
		<documentation>
		TrainingCoursesTaken is a collection of TrainingCourseTaken instances which track details on the training
 		course taken including attributes that identify the course, number of hours it will take to complete the course, cost of 
		the course, when it was taken, the final score achieved by the student, whether or not a certification is awarded and 
		course survey details.
		</documentation>
	
	<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Workforce" type="instance_child"
				 name="TrainingCourseTaken"  
		 		 elementOrder="TrainingCourseId, TrainingCourseName, TrainingHours, TrainingCost,
						TrainingStartDate, TrainingCompletedDate, TrainingTypeCode,
						TrainingProvider, FinalScoreText, FinalScoreNumeric, TrainingCreditsEarned,
						TrainingCreditTypeCode, Certification, CourseSurvey" >
		<include name="CommonElements"
				 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
				 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
		               	
		<changeLog>
			<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
		</changeLog>
		
		<notes> 
		</notes>
				
		<documentation>
	 	Tracks details on the training course taken including attributes that identify 
		the course, number of hours it will take to complete the course, cost of the course, 
		when it was taken, the final score achieved by the student, whether or not a certification 
		is awarded and course survey details.
		</documentation>
	
		<element name="TrainingCourseId" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Contains an identifier for the training course.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingCourseId>
					234
				</TrainingCourseId>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingCourseName" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Contains the name of the training course.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingCourseName>
					John Doe Painting Course
				</TrainingCourseName>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingHours" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Represents the number of hours in this training course.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingHours>
					4
				</TrainingHours>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingCost" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Represents the cost of this training course.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingCost>
					100
				</TrainingCost>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingStartDate" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
			Contains the starting date of the training course.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingStartDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
					2015-03-03
				</TrainingStartDate>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingCompletedDate" type="datetime">
			<documentation>
			Contains the date the student completed the training course.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingCompletedDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
					2015-03-03
				</TrainingCompletedDate>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the method in which the training course is administered to the student.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="TrainingTypeCodes">
				In-Person
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingProvider" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Contains the name of the person, company or association through which training is being provided.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingProvider>
					John Doe
				</TrainingProvider>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="FinalScoreText" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Tracks the final score the student received upon completion of this training course.  
			This attribute captures score in text format.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<FinalScoreText>
					Pass
				</FinalScoreText>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="FinalScoreNumeric" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Tracks the final score the student received upon completion of this training course.  
			This attribute captures score in numeric format.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<FinalScoreNumeric>
					100
				</FinalScoreNumeric>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingCreditsEarned" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Identifies the number of training credits (e.g. hours, CME units, CEU) earned upon 
			successful completion of this course.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TrainingCreditsEarned>
					15 
				</TrainingCreditsEarned>
			</example>
		</element>
	
		<element name="TrainingCreditTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
			<documentation>
			Defines the measure used in continuing education programs such as hours, continuing medical education (CME) units,
			continuing education units (CEU) or credit hours.
			</documentation>
			
			<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="TrainingCreditTypeCodes">
				Hours
			</example>
		</element>
		
		<group name="Certification" elementOrder="Type, Name, EffectiveDate, ExpirationDate">
			<documentation>
			Element in this group may be used to specify education information about the patient.
			</documentation>
			
			<element name="Type" type="string">
				<documentation>
				This can be used to categorize the type of certification provided when successfully complete t
				his training course.  For example, nursing certification types could include Clinical Nurse Specialist (CNS) 
				Certifications, Nurse Practitioner (NP) Certifications, Specialty Certifications and Assessment-Based Certificates.
				</documentation>
			
				<example>
					<Type>
						Clinical Nurse Specialist Certification
					</Type>
				</example>
			</element>
	
			<element name="Name" type="string">
				<documentation>
				Contains the official name of the training course certification.  For example, a few certifications 
				available for nursing professionals include Acute Care NP, Adult NP, Family NP, Adult Health CNS, Pediatric CNS, 
				Ambulatory Care Nursing, Cardiac-Vascular Nursing, Genetics, Medical-Surgical Nursing and Pain Management Nursing.
				</documentation>
			
				<example>
					<Name>
						Pediatric CNS
					</Name>
				</example>
			</element>
	
			<element name="EffectiveDate" type="datetime">
				<documentation>
				Contains the date the certification is in effect.
				</documentation>
			
				<example>
					<EffectiveDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
						2015-03-03
					</EffectiveDate>
				</example>
			</element>
	
			<element name="ExpirationDate" type="datetime">
				<documentation>
				Contains the date the certification will expire.
				</documentation>
			
				<example>
					<ExpirationDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
						2015-03-03
					</ExpirationDate>
				</example>
			</element>
		</group>
	
		<element name="CourseSurvey" type="OmniLink" contains="Survey">
			<documentation>
			Surveys are used to poll customers on their level of satisfaction with a service or product.  
			For the worker who took the training course, it captures specific attributes for the focus and 
			identification of a survey, the approved vendor that administered the survey, when it was taken, 
			and the list of questions and answers provided by the person who filled out the survey.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	</idsDocument>
	
	</list>	
</idsDocument>
