<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Workforce" type="instance"
			 name="WorkerBenefits"  
	 		 elementOrder="MedicalFacility, MedicalOrganization, CostCenter, AccountCode, 
					AccountName, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate, PeriodTypeCode,
					PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, CurrencyCode,
					Worker, WorkerBenefitTypeCode, WorkerBenefitSubTypeCode,
					BenefitCost, BenefitValue"
			 >
	 		               	
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>

	<customType name="SourceCode" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsCodeType"/>
	<customType name="OmniLink" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsLinkType"/>

	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>

	<notes> 
	</notes>
			
	<documentation>
 	Worker Benefits enables the customer to populate the Actual, Projected, Budget 
	or Benchmark statistics on an employee benefit by facility, organization or 
	cost center for a reporting period.  It allows grouping of benefits by type 
	and subtype.  For example, Health Insurance could include Medical, Dental, 
	Prescription or Vision.  Retirement could include subtypes Pension or 401K.  
	A benefit cost and value can be assigned to each instance.
	</documentation>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="OmniLink" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the physical medical facility associated with the worker's benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<Facility>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
			</Facility>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalOrganization" type="OmniLink" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the medical organization associated with the worker's benefit.  
		This organization consists of a group of people working together to improve methods 
		of health care delivery.
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<Organization>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Medical Center</SourceInstanceId>
			</Organization>
		</example>
			
	</element>

	<element name="CostCenter" type="OmniLink" contains="OrganizationalUnit">
		<documentation>
		An Organizational Unit is a specific group or entity for organizing or managing 
		resources within the enterprise.  Usually, these are made up of people or locations which cooperate 
		in specified objectives.  These may be Departments, Divisions, Nursing Units, Service Lines, Regions,
		 Cost Centers, etc.  A G/L Cost Center is a segment of an enterprise for which Accounting is performed 
		in the General Ledger.  G/L Cost Centers are arranged into a hierarchy which allows roll-ups and 
		drill-downs on financial information within the enterprise.  Low-level Cost Centers may be 
		Nursing Units if the hierarchy is based on physical location, or may be Service Specialty 
		if the hierarchy is based on Service Line.  Use this attribute to link to the Cost Center 
		associated with the workers benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<OrganizationalUnit>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Accounting Department</SourceInstanceId>
			</OrganizationalUnit>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="AccountCode" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the code assigned to the account associated with the worker's benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<AccountCode>
				4589
			</AccountCode>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="AccountName" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the name assigned to the account associated with the worker's benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<AccountName>
				JohnDoeAccountName
			</AccountName>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
	Contains the starting date associated with the worker's benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodStartDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-03-03
			</PeriodStartDate>
		</example>
	</element>
	<element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the ending date associated with the worker's benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodEndDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-04-04
			</PeriodEndDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the period of time as it pertains to the worker's benefit.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PeriodTypeCodes">
			Year
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for 
		any metric for the reporting period. A single IDS can be for only one Planning 			
		Category/Subcategory combination. If the customer reports this at the facility level, 
		then each IDS represents one Facility/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can 
		generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's 
		down to the cost center level, or anything and everything in between. 

		The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, 
		but how the customer uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making 
		comparisons. Actuals would capture the real statistics for the reporting period.

		If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula 
		for a hospital or organization of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for 
		different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the beginning of the 
		fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCode">
			Projected
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or 
		Benchmarks IDS's for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">
			50th percentile
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="CurrencyCode"  type="SourceCode" codeSource="OMNI" codeSet="4217">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the denomination for all amounts using the industry standard defined in
		the ISO 4217 code set.
		</documentation>

	</element>

	<element name="Worker" type="OmniLink" contains="Worker">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the worker receiving the benefit reported during this period.  A Worker is member
 		of the Workforce, such as an Employee, Contingent Worker (e.g. Independent Professionals, 
		Temporary Contract Workers, Independent Contractors, Consultants), or other Person of Interest 
		(e.g. External Instructor, External Trainee, Global Payroll, Stock - Board Member, Stock - Non-HR Employee).
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<Worker>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Consultants</SourceInstanceId>
			</Worker>
		</example>
			
	</element>

	<element name="WorkerBenefitTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		Worker benefits can include cash and non-cash compensation paid to an employee.  
		These can vary from facility to facility such as health insurance, life insurance, 
		bonus, paid vacation and retirement benefits.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="WorkerBenefitTypeCodes">
			Health Insurance
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="WorkerBenefitSubTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		Identifies a way to further categorize the worker benefit type defined.  
		For example, a worker's benefit of type Retirement could be further 
		categorized into Pension or 401K.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="WorkerBenefitSubTypeCodes">
			Medical, Dental, Prescription, Vision
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="BenefitCost" type="double">
		<documentation>
		Captures a monetary amount representing the cost of the worker's benefit 
		defined on this instance for the reporting period.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<BenefitCost>
				12
			</BenefitCost>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="BenefitValue" type="double">
		<documentation>
		Captures a monetary amount representing the value of the worker's benefit 
		defined on this instance for the reporting period.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<BenefitValue>
				24
			</BenefitValue>
		</example>
	</element>
</idsDocument>
