<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="InformationTechnology" type="xinstance"
			 name="HealthcareITOperations"  
	 		 elementOrder="Organization, MedicalFacility, MedicalFacilityLocation, PeriodStartDate, PeriodEndDate,
					PeriodTypeCode, MinutesInPeriod, PlanningCategoryCode, PlanningSubCategoryCode, Reports,
					SystemDowntime, Issues, ChangeRequests, Demand"
			 >
	 		               	
	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
	</changeLog>
	

	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>

	<notes> 
	</notes>
			
	<documentation>
 	Healthcare Information Technology (IT) Operations tracks a number of business operational metrics 
	for an organization including timeliness of reports, system downtime, issues, change requests and system utilization.  
	Additionally, it includes planning information such as projected, budget, actual and benchmarking 
	statistics at an organizational level.  If the facility and location are not specified, the reported 
	metrics apply to the entire organization.
	</documentation>
	
	<element name="Organization" type="link" contains="Organization">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the medical organization. This organization consists of a group of 
		people working together to improve methods of health care delivery.  A single IT department provides 
		support to all facilities within the organization.
		</documentation>

		<example>
			<Organization>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>IT Department</SourceInstanceId>
			</Organization>
		</example>			
	</element>

	<element name="MedicalFacility" type="link" contains="Facility">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the physical medical facility where patients receive treatment.  
		This optional attribute is specified when the reporting metrics are 
		tagged to a specific facility.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<Facility>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Hospital</SourceInstanceId>
			</Facility>
		</example>
	</element>
	
	<element name="MedicalFacilityLocation" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
		<documentation>
		If data pertains to a particular location within the facility such as a specific building, 
		it is defined here.  This optional attribute is specified when the reporting metrics are 
		tagged to a specific location within the facility.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<FacilityLocation>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>Building A</SourceInstanceId>
			</FacilityLocation>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodStartDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the starting date associated with the reported hours.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodStartDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-01-01
			</PeriodStartDate>
		</example>
	</element>
	<element name="PeriodEndDate" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Contains the ending date associated with the reported hours.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<PeriodEndDate format="yyyy-MM-dd">
				2015-02-02
			</PeriodEndDate>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PeriodTypeCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the period of time that the hours reported represent.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PeriodTypeCodes">
			Year
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="MinutesInPeriod" type="integer">
		<documentation>
		Contains the total number of minutes in the reporting period.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<MinutesInPeriod>
				4
			</MinutesInPeriod>
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		These IDS's can be used to capture Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or Benchmarks for 
		any metric for the reporting period. A single IDS can be for only one Planning 			
		Category/Subcategory combination. If the customer reports this at the facility level, 
		then each IDS represents one Facility/Category/Subcategory combination. The customer can 
		generate these at multiple levels if they so choose. IDS's at the facility level, or IDS's 
		down to the cost center level, or anything and everything in between. 

		The distinction between Budgeted (near-term) and Projected (longer term) is generally accepted, 
		but how the customer uses these categories is up to them; they just enable a means of making 
		comparisons. Actuals would capture the real statistics for the reporting period.

		If they are so inclined, they might generate "Benchmark" IDS's if say there is an industry formula 
		for a hospital or organization of their size. Multiple benchmark IDS's might be generated for 
		different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable which is probably at the beginning of the 
		fiscal year, or when industry benchmarks are issued.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningCategoryCode">
			Projected
		</example>
	</element>

	<element name="PlanningSubCategoryCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		The Planning Subcategory provides a method to generate these Actuals, Budgeted, Projected or 
		Benchmarks IDS's for different percentiles, if they exist or are calculable.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceName="TestSystem" codeSet="PlanningSubCategoryCodes">
			50th percentile
		</example>
	</element>

	<group name="Reports" elementOrder="NumberOfOperativeReports, NumberOfOntimeOperativeReports   ">
		<documentation>
		Reports is a group of attributes tracking the timeliness of operative reports at the facility over a specific period of time.
		</documentation>
		
		<element name="NumberOfOperativeReports" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of operative reports generated and distributed regardless of their timeliness at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<NumberOfOperativeReports>
					4
				</NumberOfOperativeReports>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfOntimeOperativeReports" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of operative reports generated and distributed when expected at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<NumberOfOntimeOperativeReports>
					4
				</NumberOfOntimeOperativeReports>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="SystemDowntime" elementOrder="NumberOfSystemDownEvents, TotalSystemDowntime, PlannedSystemDowntime, UnplannedSystemDowntime">
		<documentation>
		SystemDowntime is a group of attributes tracking the number of events resulting in systems going 
		offline and the number of planned and unplanned downtime minutes at the facility over 
		a specified period of time.
		</documentation>
		
		<element name="NumberOfSystemDownEvents" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of incidents that resulted in a system going offline at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<NumberOfSystemDownEvents>
					4
				</NumberOfSystemDownEvents>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="TotalSystemDowntime" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of minutes that systems were unavailable, regardless if due to planned or unplanned outages, 
			at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<TotalSystemDowntime>
					45
				</TotalSystemDowntime>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="PlannedSystemDowntime" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of minutes that systems were unavailable due to planned outages at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<PlannedSystemDowntime>
					45
				</PlannedSystemDowntime>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="UnplannedSystemDowntime" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of minutes that systems were unavailable due to unplanned outages at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<UnplannedSystemDowntime>
					30
				</UnplannedSystemDowntime>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Issues" elementOrder="NumberOfNewIssuesReported, NumberOfIssuesClosed, NumberOfOutstandingIssues, AverageIssueResponseTime,
						NumberOfResolutionsIn30Mins, MeanTimeToRepairIssues">
		<documentation>
		SystemDowntime is a group of attributes tracking the number of events resulting in systems going 
		offline and the number of planned and unplanned downtime minutes at the facility over 
		a specified period of time.
		</documentation>
		
		<element name="NumberOfNewIssuesReported" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of new issues for the IT department at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<NumberOfNewIssuesReported>
					20
				</NumberOfNewIssuesReported>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfIssuesClosed" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of issues that were closed for the IT department at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<NumberOfIssuesClosed>
					10
				</NumberOfIssuesClosed>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfOutstandingIssues" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of outstanding issues for the IT department at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<NumberOfOutstandingIssues>
					10
				</NumberOfOutstandingIssues>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageIssueResponseTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The average response time, in minutes, for the IT department for IT related issues at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<AverageIssueResponseTime>
					30
				</AverageIssueResponseTime>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfResolutionsIn30Mins" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The number of IT incident resolutions that are completed within 30 minutes from the time they were 
			reported at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<NumberOfResolutionsIn30Mins>
					5
				</NumberOfResolutionsIn30Mins>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="MeanTimeToRepairIssues" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The mean time, in minutes, to repair taken for an IT incident at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<MeanTimeToRepairIssues>
					30
				</MeanTimeToRepairIssues>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="ChangeRequests" elementOrder="NumberOfNewChangeRequests, NumberOfClosedChangeRequests, NumberOfOutstandingChangeRequests,
							ChangeRequestCycleTime">
		<documentation>
		ChangeRequests is a group of attributes tracking the number of new, completed and outstanding change requests 
		along with the average number of days to complete a change request at the facility over a specified period of time.
		</documentation>
		
		<element name="NumberOfNewChangeRequests" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of new change requests for the IT department at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<NumberOfNewChangeRequests>
					4
				</NumberOfNewChangeRequests>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfClosedChangeRequests" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of closed change requests for the IT department at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<NumberOfClosedChangeRequests>
					45
				</NumberOfClosedChangeRequests>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="NumberOfOutstandingChangeRequests" type="integer">
			<documentation>
			The total number of outstanding change requests for the IT department at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<NumberOfOutstandingChangeRequests>
					45
				</NumberOfOutstandingChangeRequests>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="ChangeRequestCycleTime" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The amount of time, in days, it takes for an IT change request to be completed successfully at the
			facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<ChangeRequestCycleTime>
					10
				</ChangeRequestCycleTime>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>

	<group name="Demand" elementOrder="PercentSystemUtilization, AverageNumberOfUsers">
		<documentation>
		Demand is a group of attributes containing the average number of users and system utilization rate at the facility over a specific period of time.
		</documentation>
		
		<element name="PercentSystemUtilization" type="double">
			<documentation>
			The total utilization rate for IT across various departments at the facility over a specific period of time.
			</documentation>
		
			<example>
				<PercentSystemUtilization>
					4
				</PercentSystemUtilization>
			</example>
		</element>

		<element name="AverageNumberOfUsers" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Contains the average number of users for the reporting period.
			</documentation>
			
			<example>
				<AverageNumberOfUsers>
					4
				</AverageNumberOfUsers>
			</example>
		</element>
	</group>	
</idsDocument>
