<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Clinical.Event" type="instance"
			 name="PatientFallEvent"  
	 		 elementOrder="EventDateTime, EventEndDateTime, Location, FallReportId,
					AssistedFallIndicator, RepeatFallIndicator, FallClassificationCode,
					FallReason, InjuryLevelCode, LikelihoodOfRepeatCode, GeneralLocation, FallDescription,
					ContributingFactors, PriorFallRiskManagement, PreventionActions"
			 backingClass="com.ibi.omni.patient.model.clinical.event.ClinicalEvent">

	<changeLog>
		<change version="1.0.0">Initial</change>
		<change version="1.2.3_3">Added ParentEvent, Encounter, CarePlanID, CarePlan, EventProviders, and  EventNote</change>
	</changeLog>

	<customType name="OmniLink" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsLinkType"/>
	<customType name="SourceCode" class="com.ibi.dib.core.ids.types.IdsCodeType"/>

	<include name="EventElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="ParentEvent, Encounter, CarePlanId, CarePlan, CCDCategoryCode"
			 appendToElementOrder="EventProviders, EventNotes, ClinicalBaseFields "/>


	<include name="CommonElements"
			 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
			 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/>
				
	<documentation>
 	Patient Fall Event is a type of clinical event tracking information regarding the patient falling.  
	It includes contributing factors and reason patient fell, level of injury sustained, likelihood of patient 
	falling again, assessment of a patient's prior fall, if any, and steps taken to lower the patient's risk of falling.
	</documentation>	
	
	<element name="EventDateTime" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Date and time the patient fell.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="EventEndDateTime" type="datetime">
		<documentation>
		Date and time marking the end of this clinical event.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="Location" type="link" contains="FacilityLocation">
		<documentation>
		Facility location where the patient fell.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<element name="FallReportId" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Identifies the documented report that details the patient's fall.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="AssistedFallIndicator" type="code">
		<documentation>
		A fall in which any staff member (whether nursing service employee or not) was with the patient 
		and attempted to minimize the impact of the fall by easing the patient's descent to the floor or, 
		in some manner, attempting to break the patient's fall. "Assisting" the patient back to bed or chair 
		after a fall is not an assisted fall.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="RepeatFallIndicator" type="code">
		<documentation>
		More than one fall by the same patient after admission or transfer to a unit.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="FallClassificationCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Classifies the type of patient fall such as if it was accidental or low risk but fell anyway.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="FallReason" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains free-form text of the reason the patient fell such as slipped on wet floor, lost footing, or became disoriented and dizzy on way to bathroom.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="InjuryLevelCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Specifies the level of injury the patient sustained from the fall.  
		ANA-NDNQI (American Nurses Association, National Database of Nursing Quality Indicators) fall-related injury categories:
		None:  Patient had no injuries resulting from the fall.
		Minor:  Resulted in application of a dressing, ice, cleaning of a wound, limb elevation, or topical medications.
		Moderate:  Resulted in suturing, application of Steri-Strips/skin glue, or splinting.
		Major:  Resulted in surgery, casting, traction, or required consultation for neurologic or internal injury.
		Death:  Patient died as a result of injuries sustained from the fall. 
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="LikelihoodOfRepeatCode" type="code">
		<documentation>
		Contains the assessed fall risk level of the patient's probability of falling a second time.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="GeneralLocation" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains free-form text of the general location where the patient fell such as patient room, bathroom, common room, hallway, etc.
		</documentation>
	</element>

	<element name="FallDescription" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains free-form text detailing the patient's fall.
		</documentation>
	</element>
	
	<list name="ContributingFactors">
		<documentation>
		ContributingFactors is a collection of ContributingFactor records.  There can be multiple factors 
		that contributed to the patient's fall.
		</documentation>
		
		<idsDocument version="1.0.0" changeVersion="0" domain="Clinical" type="instance_child"
			 name="ContributingFactor"  
	 		 elementOrder="TypeCode,  Description">
		
			<include name="CommonElements"
					 prependToElementOrder="OmniStatus, OmniStatusReason, SourceName, SourceInstanceId, SourceInstanceIdName"
					 appendToElementOrder="SourceStatusCode, SourceCreatedDate, SourceCreatedBy, SourceModifiedDate, SourceModifiedBy"/> 		               	
		
			<documentation>
			Each record captures a factor that contributed to the patient's fall.
			</documentation>
	
			<element name="TypeCode" type="code">
				<documentation>
				Contains the type of factor that contributed to the patient fall.
				</documentation>
			</element>
	
			<element name="Description" type="string">
				<documentation>
				Contains free-form text detailing how the selected factor contributed to the patient's fall.
				</documentation>
			</element>
		</idsDocument>
	</list>

	<group name="PriorFallRiskManagement" 
		   elementOrder="MostRecentAssessment, AssessmentCompletedIndicator, FallRiskScore, FallRiskMethod, AssessedFallRiskCode" 
		   dbColumnPrefix="pfrm">
		   
		<documentation>
		PriorFallRiskManagement is a group of elements capturing a patient's most recent fall 
		risk assessment, score, and probability of the patient falling based on the assessment.
		</documentation>

		<element name="MostRecentAssessment" type="link" contains="PatientFallRiskAssessmentEvent" dbColumn = "pfrm_mra_patient_fall_risk_assessment_event">
			<documentation>
			Specifies the most recent fall risk assessment event reported on this patient.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AssessmentCompletedIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="pfrm_assesment_complete_ind">
			<documentation>
			Specifies whether a Fall Risk Assessment was performed on this patient.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="FallRiskScore" type="double">
			<documentation>
			Contains the patient's most recent fall risk assessment score.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="FallRiskMethod" type="string">
			<documentation>
			Contains the method used to assess the patient's fall risk probability 
			(e.g. Morse, Conley, Johns Hopkins, Schmid, Hendrich I, II, Tinetti, Edmonson, Humpty Dumpty, 
			Tullamore, STRATIFY, Briggs, Downton, Innes, MAHC).
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AssessedFallRiskCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Contains the most recent assessed fall risk level of the patient's probability of falling.
			</documentation>
		</element>		
	</group>

	<group name="PreventionActions" 
		   elementOrder="PreventionPlanDocumentedIndicator, PatientAndFamilyEducationDocumentedIndicator, 
						 HourlyRoundsDocumentedIndicator, CallBellWithinReachIndicator, PatientMovedIndicator,
			 		     SitterInPlaceIndicator, PatientVisibleRiskIndicationCode, PatientAppropriateFootwearCode,
						 SpecialEquipmentInUseCode, AlarmsInUseCode, AssistiveMobilityDeviceCode,
						 PatientTherapyCode" 
		   dbColumnPrefix="pa">
		    
		<documentation>TBD</documentation>

		<element name="PreventionPlanDocumentedIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="pa_prev_plan_doc_ind">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether a plan to lower the patient's risk of falling has been documented.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="PatientAndFamilyEducationDocumentedIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="pa_pat_fam_edu_doc_ind">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the patient's risk of falling has been discussed and documented with the patient and family.
			</documentation>
		</element>
		
		<element name="HourlyRoundsDocumentedIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="pa_hourly_rounds_doc_ind">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether hourly rounds are performed and documented at this location.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="CallBellWithinReachIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="pa_call_bell_inreach_ind">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the patient can reach the call bell if assistance is needed.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="PatientMovedIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="pa_patient_moved_ind">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether the patient was moved to a location that lowers the patient's risk of falling.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SitterInPlaceIndicator" type="code" dbColumn="pa_sitter_in_place_ind">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether a sitter has been placed with the patient to lessen the risk of fall.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="PatientVisibleRiskIndicationCode" type="code" dbColumn="pa_pat_visible_risk_ind">
			<documentation>
			A facility may employ visual aids for healthcare personnel to more readily recognize fall risk patients.  
			Such visual aids may include a sign outside the patient's room, patient wearing a specific color of socks 
			or has a specific color of blanket, indicator on patient's wrist band, etc.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	
		<element name="PatientAppropriateFootwearCode" type="code" dbColumn="pa_pat_appropriate_footware_code">
			<documentation>
			If at risk of falling, a patient can be given footwear to lessen the risk.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="SpecialEquipmentInUseCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			If at risk of falling even in a stationary position, special equipment can be provided for the patient 
			to lessen the risk such as a low bed, side rails or a slip-resistant floor mat.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AlarmsInUseCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			Indicates whether a type of alarm is being employed to help a patient when at risk of falling.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="AssistiveMobilityDeviceCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			To lessen the risk of fall, assistive equipment can be provided to assist with patient mobility.
			</documentation>
		</element>

		<element name="PatientTherapyCode" type="code">
			<documentation>
			There are different types of therapy that may help lessen a patient's fall risk such as physical therapy, 
			exercise and training to maintain better balance.
			</documentation>
		</element>
	</group>
</idsDocument>
