<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<idsInclude name="OrderElements" type="include">	

	<element name="EventDateTime" type="OmniDate">
		<documentation>
		Date and time that the order was placed.
		</documentation>
		
		<example format="yyyy-MM-dd hh:mm:ss">2000-10-01 11:12:32</example>
	</element>

	<element name="Location" type="OmniLink" contains="FacilityLocation" keys="SourceName, SourceInstanceId" allowCreate="true">
		<documentation>
		Facility location where the order was placed.
	
		Use this element to specify a FacilityLocation in the system using the FacilityLocation's SourceName and SourceInstanceId. You cannot load FacilityLocation
		information using this element, however if the FacilityLocation is not found then a "placeholder" will be created that will contain the FacilityLocation
		when loaded.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>
			<![CDATA[
			<FacilityLocation>
				<SourceName>TestSystem</SourceName>
				<SourceInstanceId>FacilityLocationId</SourceInstanceId>
			</FacilityLocation>
			]]>
		</example>		
	</element>

	<element name="OrderNumber" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Uniquely identifies the order.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>ORD-12345678</example>
	</element>
	
	<element name="OrderTypeCode" type="SourceCode">
		<documentation>
		Distinguishes between Inpatient and Outpatient Orders, although a more granular distinction is possible.
		</documentation>
		
		<example sourceCodeSet="OrderTypeCodes" sourceCode="orderTypeCode">Order Type Code</example>
	</element>
			
	<element name="PriorityCode" type="SourceCode" codeSource="OMNI" codeSet="6055">
		<documentation>
		Indicates urgency with which the Order should be fulfilled.
		</documentation>
				
		<example sourceName="OMNI" sourceCodeSet="6055" sourceCode="asap"/>
	</element>

	<element name="OrderReason" type="string"  maxLength="1000">
		<documentation>
		Describes the reason for the entire order in free-form text.  This has nothing to do with a diagnosis.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>Free-form text block describing the reason for the Order.</example>
	</element>
	
	<element name="OrderOutcomeStatusCode" type="SourceCode" codeSource="OMNI" codeSet="6060">
		<documentation>
		Indicates the Status of the entire Order.
		</documentation>
				
		<example sourceName="OMNI" sourceCodeSet="6060" sourceCode="asap"/>
	</element>
	
	<element name="OrderDetailNumber" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Represents the order detail number.  Even though each type of clinical event order 
		only contains a single order detail record, still capture the order detail number 
		for reference.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>ORD-12345678-1</example>
	</element>	
	
	<element name="Sequence" type="double">
		<documentation>
		Represents the sequence assigned to the original order detail.  Even though each 
		type of clinical event order only contains a single order detail record, still capture 
		this sequence for reference.  Allows to see the sequence of order detail items within 
		an order by grouping by the order number belonging to all detail records.  
		
		Sequence serves to align predecessor/successor order detail items when required.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>1.0</example>
	</element>

	<element name="OrderDetailStatusCode" type="SourceCode" codeSource="OMNI" codeSet="6065">
		<documentation>
		Indicates the current point in the process of the OrderDetail item.
		</documentation>
				
		<example sourceName="OMNI" sourceCodeSet="6065" sourceCode="requested"/>
	</element>

	<element name="OrderSetNumber" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Each order detail item may belong to a pre-defined Order Set that is combined for efficiency.  
		OrderSets may be created for particular diagnoses or treatments by an individual physician, 
		or by a health system in accordance with evidence-based medicine protocols or industry best 
		practices.
		
		Some OrderSets are "Standing Orders" for particular situations, and are not placed by individual 
		Providers, but rather are agreed upon in advance by the Medical Staff.  This field contains 
		the unique identifier for the order set record. 
		</documentation>
		
		<example>ORDSET-12345678</example>
	</element>	

	<element name="OrderSetName" type="string">
		<documentation>
		Contains the name of the order set.
		</documentation>
		
		<example>Myocardial Infarction Order Set</example>
	</element>	

	<element name="OrderDetailReasons" type="SourceCodeList" contains="OrderDetailReason">
		<documentation>
		Identifies any additives introduced to the specimen before or at the time of collection. 
		These additives may be introduced in order to preserve, maintain or enhance the particular 
		nature or component of the specimen.
		</documentation>

 		<example>
		<![CDATA[
		<OrderDetailReason sourceCodeSet="OrderDetailReasons" sourceCode="Reason1"/>
		<OrderDetailReason sourceCodeSet="OrderDetailReasons" sourceCode="Reason2"/>
		]]>
		</example>		
	</element>
	

</idsInclude>
